<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>akai.gikopoi.com</title>
  <subtitle>generated by gikoru (on github: archmageakai/gikoru.git)</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-05-25T21:27:11-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/</id>
  <link href="https://akai.gikopoi.com/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <author>
    <name>akai</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/feed_reading.html</id>
    <title>My Approach to RSS/atom Feed Reading</title>
    <link href="/posts/feed_reading.html" />
    <published>2025-05-25T21:20:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-25T21:20:57-04:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In 2025, there really is not a lot of guides out there to approach efficient feed reading. There are pay-walled feed readers out there, that can sync data efficiently for all your preferred devices. I don't recommend my approach, unless you are open to a few steps... otherwise, using other methods might be nice. Personally, I do not prefer using feed readers that read based off of someone else's server, as I've encountered a lack of control in updates in feeds (&lt;i&gt;namely&lt;/i&gt;: I can't refresh the feed myself, and that less-frequented websites do not update as quick as larger/high-traffic webpages... not good for my use at all as I love a lot of de-centralized pages and small-scale blogs/BBS/etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;The feed readers I use are&lt;/u&gt;: &lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;(1) Feedbro reader, a Firefox extension&lt;/b&gt; [ &lt;a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/feedbroreader/"&gt;link here&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;br&gt; 
&lt;b&gt;(2) Capy reader, a reader app for Android (through F-droid)&lt;/b&gt; [ &lt;a href="https://github.com/jocmp/capyreader?tab=readme-ov-file#capy-reader"&gt;link here&lt;/a&gt; ] ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that I do to keep my readers in sync is that, I primarily add feeds through Feedbro. It is a lot less tedious to use PC for adding RSS/atom feeds, and Feedbro can detect feeds on pages easily. I can then export my feeds as an OPML file, for my mobile device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONLY ONE ISSUE!! The way that Feedbro exports seems to export tags and other data improperly. This is mostly a problem when I rename the title of feeds. This is an issue when I want a nice and organized set of feeds on Capy reader app on Android!!! I took it upon myself to make a python script, which I will share, to fix these OPML files from Feedbro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put my script in a directory &lt;code&gt;~/rss_scripts&lt;/code&gt; and I also save my OPML files in that same directory, as this script READS all OPML and XML files in the directory. This script will go through all files and clean them if necessary, so that your title/name changes to your feeds will sync up correctly in Capy reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that this script always outputs XML files, so that can be an indicator of which file is which. Another note, all output files will end with &lt;code&gt;_synced.xml&lt;/code&gt; as well. You can move your synced XML file over to your Android device and import with Capy reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre style="background:#1e1e1e;color:#dcdcdc;padding:1em;border-radius:8px;overflow:auto"&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#569cd6"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; os  
&lt;span style="color:#569cd6"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; xml.etree.ElementTree &lt;span style="color:#569cd6"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; ET

folder_path = &lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;os&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcdc"&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;dirname&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;os&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;abspath&lt;/span&gt;(__file__))

&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; filename &lt;span style="color:#569cd6"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; os.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;listdir&lt;/span&gt;(folder_path):
    &lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; filename.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;endswith&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style="color:#d69d85"&gt;".xml"&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;span style="color:#569cd6"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; filename.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;endswith&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style="color:#d69d85"&gt;".opml"&lt;/span&gt;):
        full_path = os.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;join&lt;/span&gt;(folder_path, filename)
        tree = ET.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;parse&lt;/span&gt;(full_path)
        root = tree.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;getroot&lt;/span&gt;()

        changed = &lt;span style="color:#569cd6"&gt;False&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; outline &lt;span style="color:#569cd6"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; root.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;iter&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style="color:#d69d85"&gt;"outline"&lt;/span&gt;):
            display_text = outline.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;attrib&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style="color:#d69d85"&gt;"text"&lt;/span&gt;)
            feed_title = outline.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;attrib&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style="color:#d69d85"&gt;"title"&lt;/span&gt;)
            &lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; display_text &lt;span style="color:#569cd6"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; feed_title &lt;span style="color:#569cd6"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; display_text != feed_title:
                outline.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;set&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style="color:#d69d85"&gt;"title"&lt;/span&gt;, display_text)
                changed = &lt;span style="color:#569cd6"&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; changed:
            output_path = os.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;join&lt;/span&gt;(folder_path, 
			f&lt;span style="color:#d69d85"&gt;"{os.path.splitext(filename)[0]}_synced.xml"&lt;/span&gt;)
            tree.&lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;write&lt;/span&gt;(output_path, encoding=&lt;span style="color:#d69d85"&gt;"utf-8"&lt;/span&gt;, xml_declaration=&lt;span style="color:#569cd6"&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;)
            print(f&lt;span style="color:#d69d85"&gt;"Updated: {filename} -&amp;gt; {os.path.basename(output_path)}"&lt;/span&gt;)
        &lt;span style="color:#dcdcaa"&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;:
            print(f&lt;span style="color:#d69d85"&gt;"{filename} has no necessary changes. File not updated."&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this guide can be helpful to some people interested in RSS/atom reading, without the need to pay for a feed reader. This doesn't fix a lot of problems with RSS/atom reading as it stands in 2025. (The pessimistic side of me would say RSS/atom is dying the slow death...) There is still the issue of not syncing up Read/Unread posts. For me, I don't mind leaving lots of my feeds unread, and I generally keep track or remember what I have read. It isn't a major inconvenience for me to have to mark all as read on the other devices if I have to. There are settings to reduce number of posts per feed, and other tweaks that I recommend that the user decide for themselves. My main objective is that I can have access to all my feeds IN AN ORGANIZED MANNER no matter what device I am using. Overtime, I will add more to my rss cleaning script as I see fit. If I find new ways to make RSS/atom reading efficient in a de-centralized and alternative way, I'll always be sure to share!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Summary&lt;/u&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add feeds using Feedbro extension on Firefox&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Export OPML from Feedbro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run Python script to output newly cleaned XML file&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer XML file to my Android device&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Import XML to Capy reader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/ex-convict_journal004.html</id>
    <title>Entry 004</title>
    <link href="/posts/ex-convict_journal004.html" />
    <published>2025-05-25T20:30:45-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-25T20:30:45-04:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the day of this post marks 7 months since I was released from prison. I am truly grateful for being out. I just talked to a friend in prison recently through a video call, and it was great to see his face again. He gets out in 5 months. We were limited to 30 minutes for the call and the call costed almost 6 USD. It reminded me that I really have it great out here, as I'm not being tracked or charged based on how long I text or write someone. I can call or video chat all day if I have the time to, really. I mean, not everyday is a walk in the park or easy, but I do have some awesome times and every time I wake up and I'm not in a cell is a victory in itself...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I accomplished a lot recently. I finished my first semester back in school, and got all A's in my classes. I went to school at only 4 months out of prison, and I was able to do it. I don't think the academic side of it was the difficult part. Some of the things I really struggled with through this academic journey were at first the fear and insecurities (not believing I was good enough), then the superiority or the boredom that ensued (from not learning enough or at the fast pace at which I thought I could handle), and eventually there came the annoyance with the bureaucratic and gatekeeper-esque nature of the system of higher education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life isn't always going to be great. Life is full of everything, and we have to take the good with the bad. I have to remind myself that a lot. Today [5/25] I got to read the JFT [ &lt;a href="/recovery/jft_txt/05-25.txt"&gt;link here&lt;/a&gt; ] and it spoke the words I needed to hear for awhile. It also inspired a lot of thoughts and wisdom, that have been brewing for awhile. While there are resentments and other negativities brewing in my head, I forget I can find a lot of the great thoughts and ideas I have. Negativity screams harshly and positivity cries softly. I think there is a point where we "know" something and then the other point where we "learn" something. Taking it even further, there is another even more important point and that is the point where we "apply" something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to emphasize this more and more, that if you feel like you are suffering or struggling with an addiction or repetitive patterns... Get Help! Reach out! For a long time, I always felt like I was running and I wanted to change, but I couldn't. It was not until I got to prison that I found out that I lived in a prison for my whole life, of my own making. With this post, I try my best to focus on post-incarceration and its struggles, as well as not forgetting where we came from and what we learned in there. Talking about APPLICATION of knowledge above is important, because in post-incarcertation we are at that point to where we need to remember everything we KNOW and LEARNED and APPLY this to our current situation. To all my brothers and sisters out there, that are struggling with post-incarceration, if you are reading this: you can do this. Whatever you are going through.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/jp1.html</id>
    <title>Sageru #jp takeover: #jp vs FSE &amp; tokiko boyz</title>
    <link href="/posts/jp1.html" />
    <published>2025-05-13T17:25:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-13T17:25:43-04:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;"&lt;i&gt;FSE is PART of #jp CULTURE&lt;br&gt;
TOKIKO IS #jp&lt;br&gt;
I AM #jp&lt;/i&gt;"&lt;br&gt;
-Akai&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, &lt;a href="https://sageru.org/irc/"&gt;sageru irc&lt;/a&gt; #jp was reclaimed by original creator Tokiko. I was given mod privileges. I did miss out on the birth of #jp , however I was very much part of the culture that embodied and inspired its creation. I was really happy to be part of another IRC channel that Tokiko made because I was part of the proto-#jp days. Unfortunately, #jp has devolved into non-Japanese culture topics, "transgooning", and other irrelevant content to what really is #jp culture. While #jp has always been friendly to all walks of life, while also maintaining a great sense of humor, there has been a regression in #jp topics and IRC in general. This is where things get interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to USE (by actually banning people that break the &lt;a href="https://sageru.org/irc/rules.html"&gt;rules&lt;/a&gt;) as well as ABUSE my mod privileges. I started awhile ago on fediverse begging for someone to buy me Dead Cells Medley of Pain bundle (includes all DLC) on my old fediverse account, but garnered little to no attention. When I came back to IRC and checked out sageru #jp, I then decided that this is the perfect place to ask. I got banned from #jp and thus this triggered a #jp takeover where Tokiko was given back what was rightfully his. Shortly after is where I was given mod privileges. I decided to take it upon myself to spam through the &lt;a href="https://fsebugoutzone.org/jp"&gt;#jp tweet bot&lt;/a&gt; that I want Dead cells and all the DLCs, and if these conditions were met that I would leave #jp. The #jp tweet bot is a part of the origins of #jp culture, and it was great to see it come back with my return to IRC. I also would ban people if they refused and banned people that were talking bad about Akai or Tokiko, etc. I decided that a purge was necessary to keep #jp in check. No-life haters reacted by flooding Sageru and joining with a couple thousand users to lag Sageru irc network. After the floods, I would continue with my demands for Dead Cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to make lots of fans, and even people who dislike me might even find my work hilarious! You're welcome! Anyway, the best thing did happen today. A fan on fediverse &lt;a href="https://fsebugoutzone.org/dsm"&gt;@dsm&lt;/a&gt; surprised me with a GOG redeem link for Dead Cells with all the DLCs! His condition was that #jp tweet bot must come back (as it has had a staggered presence amidst shutdowns from flooding). I am happy to say that I have it now installed on my Steam Deck through Heroic games launcher! (super awesome program by the way.) Even better is that, I don't have to break a promise. (I wasn't going to leave #jp if someone bought me this game... w) Check this toot out: &lt;a href="https://fsebugoutzone.org/notice/Au3vABBJldYRxmRLfs"&gt;https://fsebugoutzone.org/notice/Au3vABBJldYRxmRLfs&lt;/a&gt; if you want to see all the screen shots involved!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I've earned my Sageru bee tattoo with a Dead Cells twist to it, as Sageru #jp's most greatest CIA janitor "Akai the Cleaner" !!! Thanks again @dsm for buying me the game, as I've wanted to enjoy Dead Cells with all the DLCs. I only played the basegame with maybe one of the DLCs (switch version)... so be sure to perhaps stay tune for a review of that as well as perhaps some articles about my next hoorah with this awesome game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/dead_cells/s1.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/dead_cells/s2.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"&lt;/img&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/ghetto001.html</id>
    <title>THE CEILING</title>
    <link href="/posts/ghetto001.html" />
    <published>2025-05-01T18:00:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-01T18:00:49-04:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;IN THE BASEMENT OF MY FRIEND, THIS IS WHERE A JOURNEY MET ITS END&lt;br&gt;
THROUGH THE WINDOW IS WHERE I WOULD SEND MYSELF INWARD AND OUTWARD&lt;br&gt;
TO A WORLD WHERE SKIES SEEMED SO LIMITLESS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WHEN I LURKED IN THE BASEMENT, WHILE MY FRIEND WAS EXPANDING&lt;br&gt;
I FIND MYSELF CONTRACTING&lt;br&gt;
BUT AS I RETREAT, I LOOK UP AND I SEE LIMITS IN THE CEILING&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE CEILING WAS MORE BEAUTIFUL THAN THE SKY FOR ME&lt;br&gt;
HOPES WERE OBTAINABLE AND FAITH WASN'T NECESSARY&lt;br&gt;
I COULD TOUCH THE CEILING AND KNOW THAT I HAD REACHED THE TOP&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE CEILING WAS A PLACE I WOULD GET LOST IN&lt;br&gt;
IF IT WASN'T THAT, I'D GET LOST IN MYSELF&lt;br&gt;
WHEN I LOOK UP, I DON'T HAVE ANY DOUBT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LIFE WAS SO SIMPLE&lt;br&gt;
I DIDN'T HAVE A LOT TO LOOK FORWARD TO&lt;br&gt;
ALL I DID WAS TRY TO GO UP WHEN REALLY I WAS GOING DOWN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IN THE BASEMENT OF MY FRIEND IS WHERE I USED TO GO&lt;br&gt;
AND NOW IN THE BASEMENT OF MY MIND IS WHERE I GO&lt;br&gt;
FRIENDSHIP IS MY WINDOW OUT&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/ex-convict_journal003.html</id>
    <title>Entry 003: Survival</title>
    <link href="/posts/ex-convict_journal003.html" />
    <published>2025-04-21T20:40:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-21T20:40:36-04:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In my meditation and daily life, I've come across and found some events to be profound and remind me of some important lessons I learned awhile back. It is really important to pay attention to your surrounding and be aware of what is going on around you, for sure. You can find a lot of wisdom and knowledge just by looking around, listening, and so on. One thing that has become evident to me is that a lot of us, ex-convicts, do not really make it long out here. We succumb to drugs, alcohol, depression or other mental health issues left unchecked. It is very easy to fall into the temptations and bad influences that this world has to offer. If we don't spend time inside the walls working on our disciplines and correcting who and how much we put ourselves around the wrong people, then we are bound to go back to prison. Thankfully, at some point in my time incarcerated I really made an effort to separate my mind and my goals from what I had to do in there. I also made an effort to make sure NOT to put myself in situations where I would have to act anti-social, and I made decisions that could be looked as unpopular, knowing full-well there could be repercussions. I am not urging people to not take risks, but I am instead urging the need to assessing the risks we make. While I still do have to do things I don't want to in order to survive, I do not have to harm people or myself in that process. And I refuse to willingly do anything like that anyways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is having these boundaries and disciplines that keep me out of trouble. However, unfortunately for some of our people, the drugs, alcohol and the social pressures of the world tempt them and achieve in getting the attention of many. I really find it unfortunate that a lot of the system does not promote people getting clean off substances while incarcerated. That is a great time to take advantage of detoxing and really getting your mind back, so that when you are released you are ready to go out, live and be you. A lot of people are willing to get high or drunk by any means necessary inside, and I was definitely one of those for some time. Another thing that is crazy is that there are some people that live in prison without drugs, and live comfortable, they get in shape, they take care of themselves, have their BEST SELF in there. And shortly after getting out, they throw that away for the social pressures and lack of isolation that alcohol/drugs scream at them. I have numerous examples of this, from being inside and seeing people come back. I also see it in people that I know and meet out here now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm glad I keep my side of the street clean, and that I don't have a bus ticket to prison. A lot of people are saving up for that bus ticket back to the pen, and they don't even realize that the money and their efforts are going toward that. A lot of people don't register that their drug use or alcohol use has correlation to their past incarcerations. There is a lot of ego with wanting to "fit in" with people, being able to "hang" in social circles wher alcohol is present, etc. I know that a lot of people do know better and it is their responsibility, but it can be hard watching people fall into the cycle. They are their BEST SELVES and just with one choice, you see that VANISH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For myself as an individual, I am thankful I am able to see this for what it is. I know that something or someone or some force is bringing this to me, and that there is a reason I have to see so many fail right before my eyes. I really re-frame these terrible sights into messages or reminders. A wise man learns from others' mistakes, not just their own. I do feel bad that people like me are getting lost in the cycle, but the good that I do when I don't fall into that cycle can help myself and others that are ready to be done with the cycle. There is a certain amount of personal responsibility we have to take as ex-convicts/FIP. The system is just terrible, but as much as I can get into philosophical materialism and see validity in the case of injustice: I have to really stop for a minute and decide that I have to keep moving forward because there isn't much I can do or control in that situation. I don't want to give up on a future for people like me, where this doesn't have to happen. The other cruel side is that, there are a lot of ex-convicts that just give up the battle and they go with the easy way: go back to prison. Prison is easy for us, and it is comfortable. I write this now to say, don't give up, to myself and to others. Surviving out here is the only way barriers will be broken. We can't wait for the system to be reformed. Pay attention to what is going on around you, and you will see that, hopefully, wherever you are in life: you are where you are supposed to be to grow and learn.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/xenobladechronicles2.html</id>
    <title>Xenoblade Chronicles 2 [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/xenobladechronicles2.html" />
    <published>2025-04-14T21:50:13-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-14T21:50:13-04:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/green.png" alt=""&gt; Xenoblade 2 redeems the series by having a dynamic story, great characters, lots of content (even without DLC), a great New Game+, and diverse playthroughs for every player&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/green.png" alt=""&gt; It's good, really good. Great.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; I did not play the DLCs, this review is just about the base-game.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; Played over 300 hours of this title. 100%'d and would do it again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I tore Xenoblade Chronicles Defintive Ed a new one in &lt;a href="/posts/xenobladechronicles.html"&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;, my tone is a lot different for Xenoblade Chronicles 2! I really enjoyed this game. They fixed a lot of the issues in the previous title. The auto-attack system is not broken on either side of the game. There is also an addition to the game, where every character in the party has the option to use "Blades" which are humanoid/living beings that are paired with a weapon that are channeled to use "Arts" and do "Blade combos"... This game has a unique story-telling, and yet it also puts forth the overall theme of Xenoblade Chronicles in general. There is a careful execution of two forces overcoming their differences, and that happens on many levels. This is not a good vs evil story, and the "bad guys" are actually relatable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a "gacha-like" system with how you get Blades, aside from main-story blades or quest blades. This makes a unique playthrough for each player, and it also makes it fun to collect and 100% the game. Every Blade has their own quests and story to go alongside their quest. There are over 50 blades to obtain, and it'll keep you busy for awhile. The main story has a roughly 100 hour completion time, so this is a full-scale RPG and does stand on its own feet. The elemental system in this game isn't broken. You can battle high-level enemies (to an extent), which fixed a lot of the issues in its predecessor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an ex-convict, I really enjoyed that the "bad guys" aren't painted in a complete negative light. They are either just misunderstood or have resentments as well as unresolved issues with themselves. This game has an existential nature, and everyone is trying to find a reason to exist. This is a post-apocalypse story, and yet again the world takes place on top of large beings. Unlike the last game where its two giant beings (one biological and one mech), this game has multiple titans and allows for more diversity in biomes. There is also bustling life in cities and a great encapsulation of different cultures throughout the world of Alrest in Xenoblade 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amount of struggles, mental anxieties and trauma that exist in all the characters gives a sense of humanity in each and every part of this game. The remnants of humanity that are lost in the Xenoblade 1 post-apocalypse story are actually in Xenoblade 2's post-apocalypse story. These games are stand-alone yet they do have dimensions that make them relate, and if you have to choose to play one of them, I really recommend Xenoblade 2. I can almost guarantee I don't ever play Xenoblade 1, however I will replay Xenoblade 2 as well as get into the DLC at some point. I think that people can learn a lot about misunderstandings, overcoming mistakes, and being fearless in the face of your past experiences from Xenoblade 2, the story, and the characters. I have never had many games make me feel so many emotions and think about existence and really delve deep into what it means to exist than the Xenoblade 2. In Xenoblade 2, I was able to learn about myself and felt like I was in another world and not just a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess another thing to be warned is that, this game has some cute/comedic nature to the characters and has some comic relief, which I didn't mind, however it does deviate from the somewhat serious (yet bland) nature of the original Xenoblade game. So anti-moe people, be warned. (even though I'd say the moe-ness is super minimal, but haters gonna hate I guess...)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/xenobladechronicles.html</id>
    <title>Xenoblade Chronicles Definitive Ed [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/xenobladechronicles.html" />
    <published>2025-04-14T21:49:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-14T21:49:29-04:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; This game includes the DLC post-story, however this review does not go into the post-story DLC&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; This game sets the tone for how a Xenoblade game works mechanically as well as in story narratives, but falls short of the mark of a complete RPG&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/orange.png" alt=""&gt; This RPG is lacking in interesting side-stories/quests, and can be very repetitive in nature&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/red.png" alt=""&gt; Unrefined level/stat system, making it so you must be a few levels higher to beat enemies and generally you only overwhelm enemies or even bosses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love old-school games from Squaresoft, and Xenogears is a fan favorite for a lot of us. Some people might also be aware of the Xenosagas games that succeed those. The Xenoblade Chronicles games are the new MonolithSoft/Nintendo games to succeed the Xeno sagas. While this new chronicle does not really touch heavy on space-travel, androids, mechs, military-futurism or really much of the themes that center in Xenogears or Xeno sagas, there is some aspects of that remaining in the Xenoblade Chronicles games. This game originally was on Wii, and now is ported in a definitive edition for Switch. I'm very impressed at the remaster and port for Switch, and the control mapping as well as UI are very seamless. This possibly is a better and more comfortable way to play Xenoblade Chronicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting all the wow factors aside that we get to experience a game that had limited attention in its original Western introduction, there is a lot of concern for how lacking this JRPG is among other JRPGs and even just the RPG genre in general. There is a lot of rinse-and-repeat. Oh wow! a new biome! I bet I'll find some more fetch quests and hunt X amount of this new monster. There really are not many quests with actual substance, and there is a lack of intrigue to the world of Xenoblade Chronicles. In a game where humanity or the "Homs" struggles the Mechs "Mechons" and have to find a way forward in their world, there really is a lack of civilization. Yet, in a lot of post-apocalypse stories, there is usually a deeper appreciation for the remnants of humanity that you can find in a story in a world where humanity is on its last limb. In Xenoblade Chronicles, that desperation and emotion isn't really captured in its overworld but it is in its emotional and evocative main story-telling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worst of the worst is that there is a whole lot of redundancy in its system. You have gem-making, and these gems go onto your characters' weapons/blades and that's all fine and dandy except for one thing: there really is no purpose in 99% of these gems. In fact, I went many parts of the game without upgrading the gems and even when I did I found 0 reason to use a lot of gems except for gems increasing my crit rate. There are gems for X element damage that don't do anything or there are gems for going up against high level enemies that don't make any impact on your strategy whatsoever. That's the downfall of the battle system in Xenoblade Chronicles -- if you are above the enemies' level, you overwhelm them and if they are above your level, they overwhelm you! There are very few reasons to even want to go back and battle enemies that are extreme high-level in this game anyway, as there is such a lack of side-content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a collection system that seems cool at first, but then you realize it is just for the sake of collection. You can skip side-quests and just grind it up a bit, and then you just let the auto-attack battle system take over and don't worry much about using your skills. Just let it go on auto-pilot, eat some popcorn, and you win. Sounds like fun? No, not really. That isn't why I play games. There is no challenge mode in New Game+ to be honest, and there is really no reason to explore and no encouraging nature to want to delve deep into this game past its main story. The highlight for me was going to Nopon village, which had so much life and then after that back to being a barren "on-the-run" type game with predictable "twists."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, now I will give Xenoblade Chronicles credit for setting a good tone in story-narrative for its time and it did set up a good foundation for the other Xenoblade Chronicles games, which are a lot better (and I will review 2 and 3 shortly after this review is posted)... Xenoblade's auto-attack system with cooldowns for "Arts" skills is pretty fun and reminds me of some old school action games or old multiplayer games (like Runescape) yet more refined and stylish. I am happy I completed Shulk and friends' adventure in Xenoblade 1 because the series does coincide with the other games' themes and moral perspective. This story is a bit direct in its story theme of two forces in conflict and overcoming a Good Vs Evil paradigm to find a greater picture. The Xenoblade (in this game called the Monado) is the blade that manifests what you imagine and carves a path to the future. (woah deep) I am thankful that I played this game, but I would say it is my least favorite Xenoblade and it really doesn't do the other games justice.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/ex-convict_journal002.html</id>
    <title>Entry 002</title>
    <link href="/posts/ex-convict_journal002.html" />
    <published>2025-04-13T16:45:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-13T16:45:03-04:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="/posts/ex-convict_journal001.html"&gt;last journal entry&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about institutionalized struggles and some of my perspectives on the world. I won't say that I completely disagree with them now, but I will admit that my attitude in writing this has changed. (for now) I have on-and-off been having a lot of issues with anxiety and fear lately. I generally take a lot of my anger or fear out by shitposting or ragebaiting on Fediverse and/or gikopoi. (not as much with the latter, and generally only towards people that are fun to troll there) That's probably not the best way to deal with my issues, but there is always a lot worse. I really want to focus more on my goals with these entries than anything else in this part of the Ex-Con journal... I want to establish a place where we, as ex-convicts or FIP (formerly incarcerated people), can get help and get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;u&gt;My goals are clearly stated as, in no real order&lt;/u&gt;:
&lt;li&gt;To establish a clear definition of what it means to be institutionalized and/or suffer from post-incarceration syndrome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide medicinal/therapeutic value and resources to those of us who are coming out of an institution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Break barriers in society for the formerly incarcerated, as well as pave a way for others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a healthy, pro-active, and pro-social culture for our group, which has been marginalized and divided for too long&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combat recidivism, which has kept our people in perpetual chains and prevented them from being able to integrate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this grows and I am able to tend to the structure of the goals of the Ex-Con journal, there will be improvements and additions to the statements. I want to keep an open-mind and allow for this to not get "locked in" to anything specific. I do believe that group therapy or social support groups are good to model after. For now, this will just be me writing about a lot of my struggles as well as even my successes! I do get in my head very often, and even though I meditate and pray regularly: I still struggle to grasp my situation. I have good support in a lot of realms of my life, and I do have people to talk to. Something is missing though, and I really don't want other people that were incarcerated to go through what I've had to deal with. There is a lot of shame that comes with incarceration. In society, there are too many barriers that prevent the open discussion of rehabilitation and helping people overcome their mistakes (that includes non-criminal mistakes!!!)... Hopefully, we can make a shift in these discussions, or start the discussion where it needs to happen.
&lt;p&gt;There are things I do miss about prison, and I shouldn't be ashamed or have to hide my past because other people feel like it is "too personal" or "not appropriate." In lower-income communities or "the hood," perhaps there is more open-minds to prison or people that are formerly incarcerated. The only problem is that there is a glorification of recidivism, as well as the lifestyle of prison in a lot of circles where people are receptive to prisoners/former prisoners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I would like to address, I will alternatively use "Ex-con" or "FIP" (formerly incarcerated person/people) to describe us as a group. I don't find "ex-con" offensive, but I also see the more inclusive nature of the term FIP. The term "institutionalized" pushes even more inclusion. Whatever the term is, they are all the same to me really. I would like for terminology not to be confusing, but this is not a structured group or idea &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt;. I'm sick and tired of trying to run away from who I am and what my past is. I want to be accepted for who I am and what I've done to overcome my past. My past is apart of me, and it has made me a better person. I don't think I would hold myself accountable or live to the standards that I live without my 10 years of incarceration. I want to be able to help people leaving prisons so that they don't have to go back to prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to prevent recidivism. More FIPs that go back to prison are more reasons for society to turn their backs to us. We want to not just build up each other, but raise awareness to others in a positive way. I will try my best to make these journals not about complaining or crying. I want this to be a productive endeavor, or at least a way to put it out there what I'm going through and maybe some things I'm going to keep my mind open to. One thing I'm open to doing is reaching out to therapy, psychiatry, go out to more NA meetings, and reach out to the numbers of other FIPs (even if it takes 1000000 phone calls to get through)... If you are an ex-con and you are struggling and you are ready to get passed the gate, &lt;a href="/contact.html"&gt;write me!&lt;/a&gt; I don't know if I can help, but I can at least listen and relate to you. And to those of you who aren't us, just know that I hope you get something out of this and hopefully you are more aware of this situation now. It is going to take a lot of time to overcome, but I'm ready to keep at this and keep at my self-care. Until next time. Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/fateextellalink.html</id>
    <title>Fate/Extella Link [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/fateextellalink.html" />
    <published>2025-04-11T12:45:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-11T12:45:31-04:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/green.png" alt=""&gt; Fun hack&amp;slash musou with a good variety of characters and skill variation that keeps things interesting.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; This game is a sequel to the original Fate/Extella.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; Played on hard difficulty. Not super challenging, but I did enjoy the run.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/orange.png" alt=""&gt; If you aren't a Fate fan or want to grind for some visual novel dialogues, not the best game to invest time into.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/orange.png" alt=""&gt; the Musou dilemma: Once you've played one level/biome, you've kind of play them all; not a lot of variety in challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed Fate/Stay Night visual novel and its first anime adaptation, and while I can't say I'm a true devoted fan of the Fate series: I was super excited to play Fate/Extella Link. I knew going into this that this game would be a sequel, and I did not play the original Fate/Extella. I can't exactly knock on the story too much, as I am under the impression this game is a limited sequel. Therefore, it is safe to say that this is more about enjoying characters than it is enjoying a true full-length story. I could be wrong about all that, however I think it is more important for me to focus on the musou gameplay and entertainment I got out of this title. Also, being that most of the Fate characters are mostly archetypes of certain classes/functions and also a funny interpretation of historic figures: I feel that it isn't super important that I did not play the original Fate/Extella or any of the other games in this sub-series. If that might impede your ability to want to start here with Fate, then I'm sure there are resources that will let you know the play order that is optimal for the Fate series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say that most musou spin-offs or derivatives passed the old Dynasty Warriors are limited or really just playing Dynasty Warriors with a skin, but this game was fun enough to make me feel like I had the enjoyment of a visual novel, an RPG, and a musou game. While the story is short, the extra/optional challenges were fun as a means to grind characters and get enjoyment out of maxing social affinities, where I'd get to enjoy small moments of fun with Fate characters from even before Extella. The battle mechanics in this title are, of course, limited to musou hack&amp;slash, yet the functionality and play style of the different characters was enough to keep me entertained. The extra skills and customization made it so that there were lots of approachs to building a character, and each character plays slightly different even if they are both from the same job/class/archetype (i.e. two Sabers)... and again, it is all a matter of how fast you wanna hit Y and X and dish out combos real easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest issue I have with this title is that it isn't really inclusive to non-Fate fans. It really is just a fan-game. I don't think it is worth putting in the time if you don't already have an investment in Fate or some form of interest in it. There isn't a lot of diversity in how levels are structured. Conquer territories as is typical of a musou game. Yet, I like how stylish the movements/dashes and transport between different bases are, as well as the aesthetic/vibe of this game. If you want a good treat, and just want to take a break with a musou title that delivers a fun environment that encourages you to switch up your character line-up, then I really recommend you try Fate/Extella Link. (or even start with the previous title)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/ex-convict_journal001.html</id>
    <title>Entry 001</title>
    <link href="/posts/ex-convict_journal001.html" />
    <published>2025-04-08T11:55:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-08T11:55:00-04:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been out of prison for just a little over 5 months now. In this time that I've been out, I've mostly committed myself to listening and waiting. I journal on a lot of different topics, however I was kind of remiss to not really attempt to blog more about some of the struggles that come with being institutionalized and now adjusting to society and responsibilities. While a lot of people may downplay the amount of work it takes to adjust to outside life again, I can say that after a decade of incarceration that &lt;i&gt;a lot&lt;/i&gt; has changed, and that being out of the loop is ever-recurring. There were plenty of people who gave me a hand and supported me, and still continue to do so, and I'm grateful for that. However, there is also a great amount of confusion I have still with the way a lot of things are. Why do search engines suck so much now? Why is it that every YouTuber has to include ads in THEIR video and sponsor a product when I'm just trying to look at a longplay or some commentary about video games??? It is funny that I was informed by magazines, family and friends about some things about the internet as well as the world (and in a lot of ways these two things are interchangeable or one and the same now, but we'll get to that a bit later), and I had some idea of how things were going to be, however I didn't realize that the toxic corners that once existed on the internet is basically everywhere in the disguise of the new forms of social media and other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really don't want this post to be about how "old internet was better" or "I enjoyed this shit before you did." Truth is, old internet wasn't really better, and it was boring and malware-filled in its darkest ages. I do miss some things about the old internet, namely that the internet wasn't generally streamlined at all times through devices. We didn't have big data or 5G, and our myspace pages weren't as much of an extension of ourselves as the way someones meta accounts/google/tiktok/etc. are today. Myspace and other platforms incl. instant messengers (MSN, AIM, etc.) were more of a way to connect with others. Even Twitter, in a city or populated area, was really useful to make connections with people of common interest and just networking in general. People actually cared about other people's tweets like it was a stream of consciousness or collective mind. The algorithm has really dulled down the actual social element of social media, and so I really &lt;i&gt;try&lt;/i&gt; to avoid all those major platforms in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were smartphones before my incarceration, and I did own one. I don't know what year it really started to take hold, but now phones are really like a drug to people. People can't live without looking at their phone, or lose themselves and go into anxiety fits over not having their phone. While I do have a lot of apps I enjoy on the phone, and I do carry it everywhere: I have my reasons. It is unfortunate that in this world, it is hard to do anything without a phone now. These aren't really phones, they are just mini-computer ankle monitors. I have to keep my phone on me, as I am under supervision. If I get a call from the PO, I have to pick up and communicate. Prison is like a microcosm of this world, and this world really is a prison. Only when you free your mind, and find a safe place or refuge within the nine realms of your mind, will you be able to experience true freedom. I learned that a long time ago, and it is always a Work-in-progress and never granted -- it's a choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I choose to be master of myself, and that includes master of my phone. One day when I'm off supervision, I'd prefer maybe to only use or have access to my phone once or twice a week. I really don't like it. It's a machine full of toxic energy, and I only have fun on it when I mostly do activities such as read eBooks, read manga or play emulators. No, I don't play any of the "X-game" Go's or Gacha or Paywall.. and yes, I've given these their fair share of time AND it is &lt;i&gt;always&lt;/i&gt; worth it to uninstall those types of games as they aren't really games and are more of a "service"..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing: I'm really trying my best so that I have a good variety of social outlets. The internet can't be my only social outlet. There was often a joke about people looking down at their smartphones, when they first came out. And now that joke is the reality of this world. Every time I'm out, I look around and people just look down at the phone. Don't get me wrong, I do look at my phone in public too. It just is kind of a shame that the world's social anxieties and ineptness is like looking in a mirror almost. I remember being the socially awkward one, and now it is like cool to be socially awkward now I guess. (not really) People would rather interact with each other through their phone, and I really find that odd. I go to NA meetings, and there are people glued to their phone the WHOLE time. Now, there is a certain amount of social activity and commitment I get with being a member of NA and other social groups or 12-step meetings, but I am re-learning as well that I will continue to be disappointed with people not just in NA, but anywhere. Maybe when I have less obligations/responsibilities, I'll be able to expand on my options in social outlets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My life in prison in terms of QoL and social life was actually a lot better. Everything is right there. Now, there are limitations and lack of information. However, the internet isn't the way it was 10 years ago. The internet is full of disinformation and lots of hurdles (pay-walls) to get information. You have to be even more clever to find the inner secrets on the web, which is not really as exciting as some Indiana Jones-esque adventure or some Sherlock Holmes case solving. Prison kind of forces you to interact with people you normally wouldn't want anything to do with, and I've actually made real friendships by overcoming differences. A lot of the beauty we see in JRPG/story-based games, showing character development and growth, were actually really part of my reality. I met some of the most amazing people, and unfortunately a lot of those people can only be their best selves in prison for on reason or another. Namely, institutionalization is the main reason. I do get a little bit of connection with people at an NA meeting, which is similar to the forced interaction of prison, but the difference is that: once the meeting is over, "real life" starts back up again. In prison, you are consistently around people, and it is a good idea to built pro-social relationships in there (albeit, hard at times too) so that you consistently have positive support. I learned that we really are who and what we surround ourselves with, and that as much of an introvert that I may be: I know that how I feel on the inside does get impacted to a point by the outside world. When the outside world becomes too overwhelming for me, it is very easy to withdraw and it is a way I've protected myself for a very long time. (and not necessarily a bad thing, if in moderation or to certain extents of coping, etc.) This is a very hard paradigm to deal with. And understanding the paradoxical nature of this world was very important to me, and hopefully I can relate what I've learned in prison to being on the streets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this and you are institutionalized also, please &lt;a href="/contact.html"&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt; somehow. Two minds are greater than one, and this world really is weak right now. We don't have to let ourselves feel or think we are weak because we don't fit in with it. Let's overcome barriers together and share our successes in this new, odd digital world. (yes, I do think I am in a quasi-Bladerunner or proto-cyberpunk world, not as aesthetically grimey or cool but yet it can have that vibe sometimes...)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/prison_cell040725.html</id>
    <title>prison cell drawing 2</title>
    <link href="/posts/prison_cell040725.html" />
    <published>2025-04-08T11:54:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-04-08T11:54:32-04:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://booru.gikopoi.com/_images/00dae93496ca7ff5dee682f8afa1203e/277%20-%20akai%20blueprint%20cad%20cell%20prison%20prison_cell.png" width="300" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Moving clockwise from top left&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toilet/sink&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bunk beds w/ ladder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cabinets/shelves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table/desks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NEW "hygiene" shelf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;My thoughts on next blueprint&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well, we got us a cell door this time, so you aren't trapped in there forever. You can get out for some dayroom, yard or chow... or maybe your prison job!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think it'd be cool to get into making an isometric prison cell drawing, for more details... but I'm  having fun reminiscing with a 2d drawing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Benefits of making blueprints&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeps me disciplined, even though last drawing was 2 months ago almost exactly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fun hobby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keeps me sharp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;helps me learn more libreCAD (which can be a bit different in some ways from the softwares its inspired/derived from), as I prefer not to use bloatware&lt;/li&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/monarkdeluxeed.html</id>
    <title>Monark Deluxe Ed [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/monarkdeluxeed.html" />
    <published>2025-03-21T23:57:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-21T23:57:18-04:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt="[*]" title="[*]"&gt; Former Atlus SMT/Persona developers join Lancarse / Furyu to put out this Persona-like game, which does a great job of evoking SMT and Persona (3) vibes, yet misses the mark of being a full-expansive JRPG.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt="[*]" title="[*]"&gt; This game's battle mechanics are that of a TRPG, with some unique mechanics such as radial movement rather than typical grid-based, as well as a unique set of skills and abilities.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt="[*]" title="[*]"&gt; While I did enjoy my ~80 hours with Monark, there's not much "deluxe" about this game (just some collector's item and OST download) and the worst thing about a game that reminds you of another game (Persona) is that you end up just wanting to play that game instead...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monark is stunning the first time you enter the game. The graphics are so crisp and I can't believe I'm playing it on a Switch. There is a dark, gothic vibe to this title that makes me think of Persona 3 and all the darkness and grim aura of a Shin Megami Tensei title. You are trapped in your school "Shin Mikado Academy" by a barrier, covered by mist and also areas of the school get shrouded by mist caused by Pactbearers. As a group of the True Student Council, you go to another world through your smartphone (by calling numbers to enter battlefields), you seek to retrieve the Egos of the Pactbearers to clear the mist and free the academy from the clutches of the mist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game easily evokes Persona vibes (3, 4 and 5 mainly) ... I am reminded of Persona 3's setting a bit without being able to leave school, Persona 4's mist, and Persona 5's smartphone gateway to another world. This game does hint at being Persona-like, with a stylish characters as well as an awesome soundtrack (incl. vocal tracks that sync well in boss battles!) ... however, it truly misses the mark in this respect. While the story and concept of Monark was interesting at first, with a personality quiz to figure out which deadly sin you're most aligned with, rewarding you with a fiend party member of that sin... it is shown overtime that Monark's decision making doesn't make any real difference on story or relationships with the characters. It is very story-driven, and has full voice acting, yet it lacks the extra content that breaks it up between dungeon-crawling, story, and simulations (like a true modern Persona title)...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I can't truly call this game a Persona-like, I can say I did really enjoy the battle mechanics and a lot of the unique parts of the system. You have to prevent your characters from reaching madness gauge to 100% (your characters go into a frenzy and are uncontrollable) and also you can increase an awakening gauge to 100% (you get stat bonuses at this state)... yet if you are able to get both to 100% at the same time you reach an even greater state: Enlightenment state (even more stat bonuses and your madness is still increased so some abilities that are powerful with high madness can still pack a punch).... This unique battle system includes radial movement as well as interesting tactical combinations, deciding between a party of human members or just using fiends instead or you can mix and match both!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where Monark is lacking is its biomic diversity in battlefields and the fiends you recruit overtime don't look very different. Also, when you are outdoors at any point in the game, you can't use your right stick to adjust camera upward and look at the sky or anything. They should have just left the game to be one-stick altogether to give it a retro-feel, or just not been lazy programmers and made the camera fully accessible in all locations! The story is very anti-climactic, and really doesn't lead anywhere truly interesting. There's a lot of repetition, that seems to be content to just fill the story or add to the playthrough length. The characters' suffering and trauma is evocative throughout the breaking of their Egos, and that is the height of the story yet you can't get to know the characters outside of the main story in any side quest or side story settings. There are no side quests in Monark. There is some optional content or puzzles though. The puzzles get pretty repetitive, it is a lot of the same rinse and repeat that keeps it uninteresting as you are mostly just using the same logic every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm glad I got the experience of Monark Deluxe Ed, but I really have no idea why this game is Deluxe, as the game itself isn't upgraded at all. You just get some collector's items with the game (like a little book and digital DL of the OST... which actually: the OST is awesome...!). While I did love the nostalgia vibes I got from this Persona-inspired game, I think my desire to play a Persona game was so great that it truly distracted me from enjoying this title for itself. That's the unfortunate part of when a game reminds you too much of another game: you just want to play the other game instead. Monark is cool for being an ode to Persona from former devs of Persona, but it doesn't add too much to stand up to Persona at all. I am still happy that I got to play this stylish title, and it was worth the 80-90 hour venture.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/prisontaffy2.html</id>
    <title>Prison Taffy - Extra approach</title>
    <link href="/posts/prisontaffy2.html" />
    <published>2025-03-20T20:15:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-20T20:15:28-04:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://booru.gikopoi.com/_images/2abe7973f2bfdc2102716720cf948808/258%20-%20akai%20candy%20food%20oc%20photo%20prison%20taffy.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You might have enjoyed my &lt;a href="/posts/prisontaffy.html"&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt; on Prison Taffy and how to make it. This article is more about showing a way I get creative with the taffy, because candy is always great to be colorful and stylish. In the picture above, I made two new flavors: Strawberry and Orange. I roll part of each flavor separately and make "Taffy twists" or you can also mix pieces to have a mixed ball of flavor like shown above. Periodically, I'll be showing ways I get creative with taffy as I come up with more ideas. This was something very common in prison, and I'd love to explore more ways to expand on Prison Taffy now that I'm out here.
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/pokemoncrystallegacy.html</id>
    <title>Pokemon Crystal Legacy [Romhack Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/pokemoncrystallegacy.html" />
    <published>2025-03-19T17:59:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-19T17:59:44-04:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/green.png" alt="[]" title="[]"&gt; This is the best way to re-explore Pokemon Crystal, as this romhack does not veer away from the integrity of what made this game amazing.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt="[*]" title="[*]"&gt; This romhack strives to make a more balanced and refined experience of Pokemon Crystal, giving the single-player more power and ability to enjoy the entirety of this title. All 251 pokemon are accessible within the game, as well as Kanto is revamped and upscaled (levels).&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt="[*]" title="[*]"&gt; This romhack adds more QoL features such as running shoes, 251 pokemon sprites in overworld/menu, HM deletion, early EXP share, bigger backpack, and more.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I streamed this game on &lt;a href="https://play.gikopoi.com"&gt;Gikopoi&lt;/a&gt; in its entirety (completed all the story and pokedex!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="https://akai.gikopoi.com/image/crystal_legacy/room.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Always remember to let Mom save your money so you get cool stuff for your room!!&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the first game/romhack that I streamed to completion! I had a great experience doing so, and Pokemon Crystal Legacy was still a social experience that Pokemon always was even though it was only me playing the game. I really love that this game sticks very close to the vanilla game. There are lots of modifications to this title to allow for all 251 pokemon to be caught, as well as a slight modification in Silver's storyline (which added more flavor without taking away from the canon). There is information all over the web about this title, so look around and you'll be sure to find a good amount of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend taking your time with this romhack, and just enjoy it. There is a lot that is still the same as Crystal. It is very intuitive and you can figure out lots of the modifications out on your own. Explore, talk to NPCs, and you will be sure to complete that pokedex if you are patient and willing. Pokemon Crystal has aged so well, and the added graphics such as 251 overworld sprites for each mon was a great addition that added to the experience. I love how there is a sequence break at the point of Ecruteak City, and I can tackle badges 5-7 in whatever order I prefer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="https://akai.gikopoi.com/image/crystal_legacy/champ.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;small&gt;This is the team I used in the epic battle with Red.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were some minor issues I have with this romhack, and that is how the levels are not scaled in certain areas. You don't get access to Whirl Islands until around badge 7 and even then you cannot get the Silver Wing until you get to Kanto. The wild pokemon in Whirl Islands are all around lvl 23-25, presenting not much of a challenge on the way to lvl 60 Lugia. Other than that, I had no issues with this game. They upscaled Kanto a lot, and they made it interesting to battle a few historical trainers with Legendaries on their team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I changed my team up a lot in this romhack. I even caught a Shiny Zubat (named it "Gween") early on in the game, that I used throughout the playthrough and made a champion (as a Crobat). You can rematch with all the Johto gym leaders, and I really recommend this as a way to grind and make money FAST. As I said before, Kanto is upscaled and that includes the Legacy/historic trainers like Blue or Red. TheSmithPlays did a fantastic job at making this game balanced yet also challenging, while also making me believe I was re-experienced Pokemon Crystal in a 100% playthrough as if I was a kid again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="https://akai.gikopoi.com/image/crystal_legacy/gween.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;small&gt;I caught him as a Zubat within 10 minutes or so of playing!&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not related to this romhack, but also giving credit to Crystal Legacy for allowing me to enjoy the game to its entirety: I really love Gen II of Pokemon so much. The design is so iconic, and just feels much more complete than the original 151 in Gen I. This is the only Gen that you can traverse two regions, and this game will definitely feel more complete than any of the newer generations (even if I do enjoy the monsters in those games a lot!)... The soundtrack was so immersive, and how they have town music for two regions as well as awesome Kanto battle music is what makes this game so dynamic for its time. The spritework on the base game and then the romhack sprites/animations for each mon (as said before) just blends right in with the style. Amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="https://akai.gikopoi.com/image/crystal_legacy/diploma.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Diploma of completion of Pokedex... Make sure to go find Mew after you get this!&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;b&gt;*not*&lt;/b&gt; my last romhack by any means! And it is also &lt;b&gt;*not*&lt;/b&gt; my last Pokemon Crystal romhack either! My next hurrah will be Pokemon Crystal Clear, which is vastly different in design objectives from this romhack. I'm excited to get to it, but I also can't wait to replay Pokemon Crystal Legacy in its entirety all over again someday as well.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/fireemblemwarriors.html</id>
    <title>Fire Emblem Warriors [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/fireemblemwarriors.html" />
    <published>2025-03-19T16:55:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-19T16:55:16-04:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/orange.png" alt="[!]" title="[!]"&gt; This game is a spin-off of Fire Emblem with Dynasty Warriors mechanics, a collaboration of Int. Systems and Omega force / Koei.. so be warned! No Tactical RPG found here.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt="[*]" title="[*]"&gt; This game includes characters from Fire Emblem 1 (shadow dragon), Awakening, and Fates as well as some new characters, in the new setting of Aytolis.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt="[*]" title="[*]"&gt; This game is limited mechanics-wise... (perhaps due this title being released on 3DS as well as Switch)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among all the early Dynasty Warriors as well as early spin-offs (such as Dynasty Warriors Gundam), I found it really interesting to see a traditionally turn-based tactical RPG series, for this instance Fire Emblem, made into an action RPG / hack &amp; slash Musou title. I think with all the awesome weapons, stylish characters, as well as the beautiful, war-driven, tactics-centric world of Fire Emblem is a perfect place to do such a thing! With Dynasty Warriors, there is a sense of historical fiction, and they've even dived in Western cultures in newer titles. However, when I play games, I love to also go to fantasy worlds or just other worlds in general. So, the Dynasty Warriors style with a world like Fire Emblem seems very compatible for a spin-off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure why this title just misses the mark in some ways. I do enjoy being able to have a variety of characters to play from, as well as a story mode and historical mode (where you can get a bit of retro in as you delve into older games of Fire Emblem and have historic battles from those games)... however, Fire Emblem Warriors seems to be very limited in terms of action. It might be because this game was also released for 3DS, but there are certainly a lot of limitations with this title as well as a lacking camera control in the right-stick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the new era of Tactics RPGs, there is an added bonus of building support levels or relationships with other characters as well as characters building support levels between each other. This game does have that, however it is very limited and only gives you a support level conversation once the support level is maxed out. Even the dialogue in the historic mode is very limited, making the grind to the end not really worth it. Fire Emblem Warriors lacks great rewards for tremendous amount of grinding. If you like to complete games 100% for the sake of completion, then you might not have trouble with this title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The characters' mechanics control in this game is fun and exciting for the most part, and mechanics aren't too bad, but there really is just pressing combos of X and Y. This game doesn't truly utilize the potential of a modern control layout. You don't need to unlock all the combos for a character on the hardest settings, and spamming might even be the safe way to go anyways in Lunatic mode. There is a lack of added difficulty, even with Classic mode (characters really will die, just like in traditional Fire Emblem)... The playthrough of the story mode in this title was around 20 hours. It is a very short story, but this title can keep you busy for maybe 90-100 hours if you decide to do everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story and world of Aytolis are more of just an excuse to allow for a mashup of Fire Emblem characters joining up in one world, but I can't exactly dislike this because it is really cool to have Marth, Khrom, and female Corrin all on one team. There certainly are OP characters and classes, such as any of the bow-using characters. Spam and more spam, is a sure win with a bow-user. Sure, you can change it up or keep yourself from stacking up the OP characters, but even then there is a sure path to victory as long as you keep hacking and slashing. True: this is the dilemma that Musou titles might have, however there are other Musou titles that DO have challenges and are not spam-to-win (including some of the newer clone titles such as Persona 5 Royal or FE Warriors: Three Hopes)... From all the new Musou clones/spin-offs that I've played, it is safe for me to say that Fire Emblem Warriors is limited by the hardware it was intended for.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/megaman11.html</id>
    <title>Mega Man 11 [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/megaman11.html" />
    <published>2025-03-16T11:19:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-16T11:19:39-04:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/orange.png" alt="[!]" title="[!]"&gt; This game is just Mega Man for noobs basically, and doesn't add anything to stand up to new platformers and also can't beat older Mega Man games in the core series.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/orange.png" alt="[!]" title="[!]"&gt; "Slap and paste a skin over older Mega Man titles..." Capcom has given up on Mega Man basically... sad.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt="[*]" title="[*]"&gt; This game has lots of achievements and fun to enjoy, collect-them-all type trophies for those that are completionists and want to 100% it all. For those that like a platforming challenge, maybe you can have fun with that. For me, I'd rather just go back to Mega Man 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like the Mega Man X games the most, as all these titles have awesome customizations for platforming, fast-paced action, more story, as well as its more "mature" nature. However, I do got a special place in my heart for the core games, especially Mega Man 2. I was excited to play Mega Man 11, but was truly disappointed. There are hardly any cutscenes or story to make this game feel modern. I don't mind the 2d platforming style that this game retains, and in some ways its polished and looks pretty. I don't like how 2d platforming has been mostly replaced by 3d platforming, especially in the big platformer titles (mario &amp; sonic). While I think 3d platforming has a time and place, I love the 2d platforming (metroidvania especially). Disappointing for this game is that it just feels like earlier Mega Man titles with a new skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I did enjoy the energy of the boss battles as well as the new soundtrack and graphics overall, I know the fans deserve a lot better. Why can't there be decent story cutscenes to follow rather than a generic Mega Man story? I love the upgrades and changing the suit as well as all the other things that make it a Mega Man game, but I can't help but feel like Capcom created Mega Man 11 as a quick cashgrab. The fans deserve so much better. This is a trend in a lot of newer Capcom titles (incl. MvC), where capitalism and cheap/quick programming beats taking a chance with a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from Mega Man 11 being just Mega Man with polished graphics and sound, there is a decent amount of achievement trophies and other platforming challenges that can be fun, if you like to play platformers to 100%. At least there is a decent amount of replayability for the fan of the Mega Man platforming style. This game doesn't make it super easy the way the new Mario or Sonic games do. It still has decent amount of learning curve, yet can be a bit more forgiving than earlier titles (Mega Man II). While I don't completely like all of that, I get it... and at least I can be happy that the series of Mega Man hasn't fallen completely to the pressures (making the game playable/easy for kids) that Mario or other popular platformers have fallen to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capcom has disappointed a lot of fans with the lack of content or new in their newer titles. Typical graphical boosts and just slapping a skin over a title is the go-to, and also a slight change to mechanics takes away from the integrity of their games as well. While it does make for a more forgiving title (where if I jump from point A.1 or A.2 and get to point B.1), I still like the challenge of Mega Man 2 where I really have to be careful where I execute my jumps and manuevers. Mega Man core games have always been more "technical" platformer which is fitting for the tech/robotic-style of the game, whereas Mega Man X has been more action/fast-paced and gear-customization oriented... Capcom should not break the formula that works, where core games and X are like a yin-yang, yet they need to put more energy into the Mega Man core series as it is getting to a point where it is so repetitive that it isn't even worth the play. Even the later Mega Man X titles have lost their novelty and need to be re-evaluated. Overall, stay away from newer Capcom titles. For the core Mega Man games: I recommend Mega Man 2 and for the Mega Man X games: I recommend Mega Man X4. These are great stand-alone titles that evoke the true integrity of the Mega Man franchise!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/castlevaniaanniversarycollection.html</id>
    <title>Castlevania Anniversary Collection [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/castlevaniaanniversarycollection.html" />
    <published>2025-03-15T22:37:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-15T22:37:05-04:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/green.png" alt="[]" title="[]"&gt; This title carefully addresses the FIRST generation of Castlevania, from its 8 bit era to the start of the start of the 16 bit era. It also includes never-before-released in North America: the original Kid Dracula.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt="[*]" title="[*]"&gt; All Titles: * Castlevania (NES, 1986) / * Castlevania II: Simon's Quest (NES, 1987) / * Castlevania III: Dracula's Curse (NES, 1989) / * Super Castlevania IV (SNES, 1991) / * Castlevania: The Adventure (Game Boy, 1989) / * Castlevania II: Belmont's Revenge (Game Boy, 1991) / * Castlevania: Bloodlines (Sega Genesis, 1994) / * Kid Dracula (Famicom , 1990) **&lt;i&gt;please note I write American names for console such as NES/SNES if it has NA release, and list Japanese name such as Famicom to distinguish that this was not released in NA.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt="[*]" title="[*]"&gt; This collection is not for those who are Symphony of the Night or the new era of Castlevania fans, as it only includes released from 1986 to 1994 (and then again, it isn't even a complete collection of all titles in that time period) ... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love Castlevania, and while there are numerous ways to access old titles besides the Anniversary Collection: I did not have that option being in prison. This was a great way to replay older titles I love as well as get to play Kid Dracula for the first time! It is a bummer that there is not even one Castlevania collection that includes Symphony of the Night. (at least there is an Advanced collection!) I think that these collection titles are a nice way to immortalize the titles of Castlevania, as we live in a world where 70% of games must be pirated and modified to even be played due to DRM or lack of support for new systems. I hope that Konami continues to at least release collections of their older titles, rather than do what Nintendo (and even Sega decisively taking their titles off other platforms to promote theirs) does with their cloud gaming services. I do believe in the rights of ROM ownership as that is the best way we can immortalize old titles, however I guess a collection title is better than Konami raking in monthly cash from subscriptions. It is also a shame that Konami does sit on their IPs so much, but that is a topic for another article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that this review was helpful or at least a blast from the past or somewhat interesting history from my perspective. I try to make Castlevania a tradition I play at least in October or Halloween time. I didn't get to last time as I was just released and adjusting, and life gets life-y. However, my last Halloween in prison was spent playing Castlevania anniversary collection, and I'd have it no other way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be individually reviewing each title from this collection starting now...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* &lt;u&gt;Castlevania&lt;/u&gt; (NES, 1986)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AKA  / Akumajou Dorakyura (JP) [lit. Devil's Castle Dracula].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the title that started it all for Castelavania. I really forget how advanced this was for its time, and how well it has aged. It almost makes me think, "Wow! I can't believe this is a game from the 1980s..." With lots of weapons/items to choose from, and unique/diverse boss mechanics, it really makes you amazed at the technical prowess of Konami developers. You play as Simon Belmont in this title and as a member of the Belmont clan and inheritor of the Vampire Hunter whip, it is your inherited duty to battle Count Dracula. The soundtrack is so iconic, with Intro, Bloody Tears, and Vampire Killer... so amazing that these titles are so amazing they get renditions in newer versions of Castlevania and even in the transition from the Heavy metal aesthetic to the more Gothic new era of Castlevania, you still have the integrity of a Castlevania game that doesn't try to be anything else for the sake of capitalism or superficial goals... This isn't my favorite of the NES era by far, but it definitely set the bar high for platformers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* &lt;u&gt;Castlevania II: Simon's Quest&lt;/u&gt; (NES, 1987)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AKA   / Dorakyura II: Noroi no Fuuin (JP) [lit. Dracula II: Seal of the Curse].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not strictly a platformer, but more of an RPG with platforming and Castlevania mechanics!!! Simon's Quest is a direct sequel to the first Castlevania game. Before his demise, Dracula has placed a curse upon Simon, giving him an early death unless Simon collects all of Dracula's body parts and revives him. In this title, you get to interact and do typical RPG communication puzzles alongside platforming challenges to then finally battle Dracula again after you have revived him. This title is definitely different than any other Castlevania game, which is not necessarily bad, but if you are looking for the classic Castlevania style: this is not exactly it. I urge RPG fans to give this title a try for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* &lt;u&gt;Castlevania III: Dracula's Curse&lt;/u&gt; (NES, 1989)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AKA  / Akumajou Densetsu (JP) [lit. Legend of the Evil Demon Castle] -- same title as first title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among my favorites of the Castlevania games and my favorite in the NES era is this title. You play as Trevor C. Belmont, an early/ancient Belmont clan member from the 15th century! (The first two in the core series were in the late 17th century) This title is awesome because you have other playable characters you can get depending on which locations you go to. These characters are: Sypha Belnades, Grant Danasy, and Alucard. I really enjoy the later boss battles in this game, especially the boss battle where you battle a shadow of yourself (which also transforms to the other characters when you transform...), and these later boss battles really challenge you so much in different ways. The back-to-back challenges and the non-linear nature of this game are what set it apart from a lot of titles of its time. I love all the different abilities of the other characters and the unique re-playability that this title offers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* &lt;u&gt;Super Castlevania IV&lt;/u&gt; (SNES, 1991)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AKA  / Akumaj Dracula (JP) [lit. Devil's Castle Dracula].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is basically a remake title, before remakes were cool! You play again as Simon, and with a new 16 bit graphics and sounds as well as new mechanics like using the Vampire Hunter whip to swing. The mechanics are very smoothed out in this title, and they brought a lot of new life to the levels from Castlevania I. There is definitely a bit more of a "heavy metal" vibe to these graphics than ever, and it really shows well in the 16 bit era. There isn't much to say about this title besides that Konami mostly probably used this opportunity to transition to the 16 bit era more than anything. Going back and remaking a great title from before and making it even better in some ways. There still is a certain novelty of the first Castlevania title as well as with its own difficulties due to the hardware and development limitations it may have had that make it so unique, so I definitely prefer the first Castlevania to this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* &lt;u&gt;Castlevania: The Adventure&lt;/u&gt; (Game Boy, 1989)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AKA  / Dracula Densetsu (JP) [lit. The Legend of Dracula].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This title is black/white as it is game boy classic. There are a lot of limitations with these game boy platformers, and there aren't even sub-weapons you can get in this title. It is almost like Castlevania on training-wheels to be honest. Even so, it is worth the challenge for anyone willing to take it. Early Game Boy is even impressive in its own ways, but it is also kind of a downgrade and the other Castlevania titles definitely ruin my interest in exploring the Castlevania Adventure titles. Castlevania didn't get a great title until the Game Boy Advanced era anyway...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* &lt;u&gt;Castlevania II: Belmont's Revenge&lt;/u&gt; (Game Boy, 1991)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AKA  II / Dracula Densetsu II (JP) [lit. "The Legend of Dracula II].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher is at it again, and this time he seeks revenge against Dracula for turning his son Soleil into a demon. Dracula turns into a thin mist at the end of the previous title, and was able to assume human form again through Soleil's sacred powers. In this title, they at least incorporated sub-weapons, however only the axe (or cross in JP or EU versions) and holy water (better than nothing I suppose). This title isn't much of a step forward from the first, but it is Konami's best attempt at a contending platformer title in the handheld market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* &lt;u&gt;Castlevania: Bloodlines&lt;/u&gt; (Sega Genesis, 1994)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AKA  Banpaia Kira (JP) [lit. VAMPIRE KILLER].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great 16 bit title. You can play either as John Morris (a descendant of the Belmont clan) from Texas, USA or Eric Lecarde (a friend of John Morris) from Segovia, Spain... You are primarily trying to prevent the niece of Dracula Elizabeth Bartley, brought back by Witch/Sorceress Drolta Tzuentes, from bringing her Uncle back. And as we all know where this leads, an ultimate fight against Count Dracula at the end as usual. The mechanics of this game are very smooth/clean. I especially like the new weapon, using the Spear from Eric Lecarde is awesome. While this title doesn't have as many playable characters as Castlevania III, having the option of two at the start menu is a nice addition. This is the last title in the old generation of Castlevania (but is argued also as the start of the new generation due to its European title being labeled the new gen) as well as the first title with Michiru Yamane as composer. She would go on to work with on Castlevania titles for around another two decades. Definitely an inspiration to me working with PSGs or chiptune sounds!!! (and as a pianist)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* &lt;u&gt;Kid Dracula&lt;/u&gt; (Famicom, 1990)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AKA   / Akumajou Special: Boku Dracula-kun (JP) [lit. Demon Castle Special: I'm Kid Dracula].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first time playing the title. I'm reminded of Megaman mixed with Castlevania. This title is funny and bright compared to what I'm used to in a Castlevania game... There is a lot of color to this title, and a lot more playfulness. Don't let that fool you though, this is still classic metroidvania and you have to bring your A-game to beat this title. The bosses are funny in this game, yet still have the challenge of figuring out their movements and weaknesses. I really recommend Kid Dracula to anyone who wants to play a lite version of Castlevania with some new additions to it as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/End review.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/prisontaffy.html</id>
    <title>Prison Taffy</title>
    <link href="/posts/prisontaffy.html" />
    <published>2025-03-08T02:24:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-08T02:24:02-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://booru.gikopoi.com/_images/0024189cb4920c66fd8863eece9171b1/245%20-%20akai%20akai_food%20prison%20prison_taffy%20taffy.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;u&gt;Ingredients&lt;/u&gt;* :&lt;br&gt;
~230 mL - powdered coffee creamer (classic/null flavor)&lt;br&gt;
~30 mL - water&lt;br&gt;
~3 ct. - single mix packets of skittles green apple juice**&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

* &lt;i&gt;these ingredients will vary depending on which products you use, as well as if you prefer stronger or lighter flavor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;
---&gt; &lt;i&gt;lighter flavor add more creamer / stronger flavor add more juice&lt;/i&gt; &lt;---&lt;br&gt;
** &lt;i&gt;you can use any juice that you would prefer. I prefer to use singles packs as I find some of the best flavors compared to larger drink mixes in a tub.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
(( Note: This recipe could potentially work without the use of water and instead of powder drink mix, you could use a liquid drink mix... however to stay with the integrity of how we made this in prison, I wanted to demonstrate it with juice packets and water. We used varieties of juice singles, incl. state-issued ones from the kitchen, crystal light juice, sunkist, orange crush, skittles, jolly rancher, starburst, hawaiian punch, kool aid ... ))
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;u&gt;Directions&lt;/u&gt; :&lt;br&gt;
[1] Put a decent amount (about half) of your powdered coffee creamer, your juice mix of choice (varies on amount, figure out what you prefer: more or less flavor) in a bowl or mixing vessel of your choice ... &lt;br&gt;
[2] add 30 mL of water (yes not that much water, and even then maybe add it in increments to be safe) in a bowl &lt;br&gt;
[3] Start mixin' and add more creamer as you go ... &lt;br&gt;
[4] you will notice at first you probably have a more gritty consistency of taffy ... &lt;br&gt;
[5] don't give up, you will get passed this gritty phase, so keep adding creamer and mix!! &lt;br&gt;
[6] Once your taffy has become less gritty (and therefore not really sticky at all) .. you can play with it with your hands and knead it ... make sure to knead it into all the extra creamer in your bowl .. &lt;br&gt;
[7] you should have a nice neat ball of taffy now from kneading and rolling in your hands &lt;br&gt;
[8] you can even roll on a surface to add more creamer easily if you want &lt;br&gt;
[9] you may notice that this will make the taffy a lot more consistent overall &lt;br&gt;
[10] you should have mixed all your creamer into this ball of taffy, and now your taffy is ready to be ate if you want at this point, although i like to let it sit and get a bit harder&lt;br&gt;
[11] Here, I rolled the taffy again&lt;br&gt;
[12] I use a kitchen knife to cut the taffy into pieces to be ate &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

test out your taffy, give yourself a treat. &lt;br&gt;
Not enough flavor? you can add more juice! &lt;br&gt;
[ or ] &lt;br&gt;
Too much flavor? add more creamer! &lt;br&gt;
knead and roll!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Please note that this taffy won't be turning into cement any time soon, but do be sure to eat within 3-4 days.. Haven't tried refrigerating this stuff or any of that or even tested on long-term fresh, etc. I am not responsible if you get sick, just so you know! I prefer to wait about a day before eating most of it, I do like to sample a bit because it is so delicious. After about a day, I think it is just about perfect for me.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There is a lot more we can do to customize our taffy and get even more creative, but the purpose of this post is to get you an idea of how to get started in your taffy making journey. Please be sure to keep an eye out for more recipes on the gikoverse wiki [ see &lt;a href="https://wiki.gikopoi.com/r/CategoryFood"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; ] as well as looking at prison food wiki article [ see &lt;a href="https://wiki.gikopoi.com/w/PrisonFood"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; ] ... or you can follow atom/rss :3
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/synthetic_collapse_project_demo.html</id>
    <title>synthetic collapse project demo [Grindcore collab]</title>
    <link href="/posts/synthetic_collapse_project_demo.html" />
    <published>2025-03-02T01:51:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-02T01:51:56-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NEW RELEASE!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://applecamp.bandcamp.com/album/akai-the-archmage-x-uxsxoxtxlxsxfx-synthetic-collapse-project-demo"&gt;&lt;img src="https://booru.gikopoi.com/_images/227be64dfdda828d5abee806449df07f/242%20-%20akai%20albumart%20chinchilla%20dubbz%20grindcore%20hatsune_miku.png" width="300" title="Download from applecamp bandcamp page!"&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;u&gt;Akai the Archmage x UxSxOxTxLxSxFx&lt;/u&gt; -&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;synthetic collapse project demo&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;with assistant chinchillas&lt;/b&gt; and ft. Hatsune Miku&lt;br&gt;
&gt;grindcore, glitchgrind, atmospheric dnb&lt;br&gt;
[ &lt;a href="https://applecamp.bandcamp.com/album/akai-the-archmage-x-uxsxoxtxlxsxfx-synthetic-collapse-project-demo"&gt;download at applecamp.bandcamp.com&lt;/a&gt; ]
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a project demo that I've been working on with UxSxOxTxLxSxFx, and we've been talking about collabing for a long time. Finally our first collaboration is here, and it was a blast working with them along with Hatsune Miku and the chinchilla friends. Thank you to everyone who helped out and all the support. (you know who you are) This project demo is on the applecamp records label bandcamp page linked above, so be sure to download it there for free (or donate if you want). I have a lot of other projects and ideas, so I look forward to releasing those whenever I can. Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** &lt;u&gt;Bonus content&lt;/u&gt; **&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is bonus content collectables included in the demo's folder. You will need to convert Track 05 and 06 from .wav to .bmp ... Here is the process you need to unlock your collectables:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* 1. Download Audacity Portable 2.4.2 [ this is where I downloaded : &lt;a href="https://audacity-portable.en.uptodown.com/windows/download/2491023"&gt;link here&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* 2. Download the demo as WAV files on bandcamp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* 3. Drag and drop one track (either 05 or 06) into a new Audacity window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* 4. File -&gt; Export -&gt; Export Audio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* 5. In Export Audio window: Set "Save as type" to "Other uncompressed files"; "Header" to "RAW (header-less)"; "Encoding" to "U-Law"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* 6. DO NOT SAVE YET. Set the file name to your_filename_here.bmp (as long as the file extension is .bmp, this will work), and then Save.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* 7. You can now repeat these steps for the next track in the folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you followed through with these steps, you should have two .bmp files with some bonus collectable content, rare and secrete stuff! Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/sao_hollowrealization.html</id>
    <title>Sword Art Online: Hollow Realization Deluxe Ed [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/sao_hollowrealization.html" />
    <published>2025-02-28T22:41:08-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-28T22:41:08-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/green.png" title=""&gt; A single-player fake-MMO action RPG that has lots of optional content and DLC included, with dating sim elements (Gotta Get That CG!), as well simple yet fun, stylish battle mechanics.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" title="*"&gt; Non-SAO fans might not exactly like this title, as it references a lot to the anime.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/orange.png" title="!"&gt; For gamers that prefer a challenge, there isn't a lot to this title and it remains very easy, even through the DLC/post-game. Grind-to-win is the only issue I have with this title.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/orange.png" title="!"&gt; If you do not like visual novels or that style of dialogue, I recommend to steer clear. Animations/cinematic scenes are minimal in this title.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This title is my first of the Sword Art Online games. I will say that, while I do prefer JRPG/turn-based games, I do enjoy an action RPG if it is well-executed for my tastes. This action RPG is very simple in nature, but it is stylish enough and customizable for my tastes. I love the variety of weapons and characters available to you off the bat. You get to customize your character decently. The default is Kirito, however, and they only have male-audio for the main character so if you play a female, you have to mute the main character audio. Also, cinematics/animation/CG scenes only show Kirito, some characters refer to you as Kazuto (which is poor programming, not making the text for main character refer to a name variable), etc... so basically the main character is Kirito whether you decide to look different or not. I still rolled with a custom character anyway, but that is just poor programming as well as budgetting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story follows a sort of mash-up of characters from the movies as well as the core series. This story is not canon. There isn't too much depth to the story, as it is mostly just story of treating people as well as NPCs with respect, and typical friendship tropes that most anime has. I think where most of my entertainment was in this title was the dating sim aspect. I like how early into the game you can unlock CG if you know what you are doing. It didn't take long for me to figure out the best ways to max affection for each girl and become Harem King Kirito. The real fun isn't the main story, but all the side content that exists for fans of the series and the characters. Please note, most of the content here is told through visual novel style dialogue, and there is only a minimal amount of cinematics/animation. The UI for this game is a bit under-developed or simple, but I actually enjoy that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus content and DLC from the Deluxe Ed had a lot of fun quests and battle modes. There are a lot of puzzles and labyrinths once I got to the first DLC that reminded me of FFXII and old Zelda games. You can get a lot of cool weapons, and it forces you to want to not just use dual-wielding. (explore other options) Ultimate weapons and combos were very cool to get and check out. A very common problem a lot of games have now, however, is that there is a lot of equipment but not a lot of uses for those equips. Even without the ultimate weaponry, you can do just fine against even the most difficult of mobs. This game isn't very difficult, and the party members (up to 4 in party incl. you) is not very smart. The battle mechanics are fun, but they are simple. There is a lot of redundancy in the skills and system. This title is very repetitive, grind, rinse and repeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from the simplicity (which it isn't necessarily a bad thing to have a simple system in a game) and looking past the redundancy, I can say that the 100+ hours I invested were worth it. I still can go back and do a lot more too. I got what I came for though, which was enjoying story content and CG. I won't cancel out looking into any other SAO titles in the future, and hopefully I find one with more of a challenge. I enjoy the MMORPG concept, however I do not like the time investment (or money investment). Being able to have a bit of that nostalgia-feel of "being in an MMORPG" was fun, and Hollow Realization let me do that. The single-player fake-MMORPG style needs to be implemented more. Games like FFXII set the bar for that style, and it faded away for whatever reason. I love how I can play at my own pace and grind when I want, and a subscription fee or the social demands of an MMORPG are too much if you want to self-care and live the human experience. Hopefully, developers and gamers can learn from the example that this title pushes forward, and greater implementations of this style of game can happen!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/pokemonday29.html</id>
    <title>Pokemon Day Japan 29 Years</title>
    <link href="/posts/pokemonday29.html" />
    <published>2025-02-26T18:49:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-26T18:49:26-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Happy Pokemon Day!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;2/27/96&lt;/u&gt; - &lt;i&gt;Pokemon Red and Green&lt;/i&gt; were released for Gameboy in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These games were not localized and released (under Red and Blue titles in the West) until later, but it is this day that we celebrate the birth of a franchise that changed a lot of our lives. These are not necessarily the greatest in the core series by far, but they set the stage. I have my criticisms with the direction of the newer titles, but this article is more about nostalgia and giving thanks to 29 years of Pokemon. Today, there is still much to enjoy in the new of the series and a lot of the old worth exploring and re-exploring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first adventure in Pokemon was Blue version, and I chose Squirtle as my starter. I was very drawn to water types as a kid, as I really enjoyed the color blue mostly. My favorite game of all time is Crystal version. I love all the regions of Pokemon. I enjoy seeing the new monsters, even if I don't exactly enjoy a game. I am thankful that Pokemon is still relevant today, and that I get to have fun with my friends just talking about Pokemon. The fact that Pokemon is a conversation topic and that it isn't pushed to the side like so many other series; it truly is a blessing. Currently, I am playing a Crystal romhack titled Pokemon Crystal Legacy, which stays true to the core of the game while adding conveniences for playing single-player on an emulator. I often stream Pokemon Crystal Legacy on gikopoi, and am currently in the post-credits part of the game hopping between Kanto and Johto (just got the magnet train unlocked). I am also re-playing Pokemon Black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pokemon is part of my life, and I will not be surprised to see Pokemon on my way out of this life. While I am reluctant to buy or support some of the future directions of the series, I will not say that I am going to close myself out entirely. I will be keeping aware of the new generations, and play the games when I can. Pokemon has brought a lot of great people and things into my life, and I will always be happy to share that experience with anyone. I hope you guys enjoyed this session of Game Corner topics, as I'll be talking about my thoughts about news or just simple reflections on games/series I really enjoy. It was an honor to have Pokemon Day be the start of a new topic here on the blog.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/runefactory5.html</id>
    <title>Rune Factory 5 [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/runefactory5.html" />
    <published>2025-02-25T22:21:23-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-25T22:21:23-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/orange.png" alt="[!]"&gt; This game isnt the worst or the best farming sim game. This is the most graphically polished and pretty Ive seen for a farming sim, but it lacks a good balance of actual meaningful content.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt="[*]"&gt; There isnt a lot of story content in this game, however there is lots of activities to do, skills to raise up, and theres lots of grinding  so if that is not your style of game, I do not recommend the Rune Factory titles.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt="[*]"&gt; If you like dating sims, this is a great title. Theres lots of choices in Rune Factory 5, and all romance options are available to male or female protagonist in this title.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt="[*]"&gt; In my opinion, this is Stardew Valley on JRPG crack.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game was my initiation to the Rune Factory games. Im familiar and played a lot of the Harvest Moon titles, and Im also a huge fan of Stardew Valley [see my review &lt;a href="/posts/stardew1.5.4.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;], but I would say that Rune Factory does add a little bit of new to the conversation. Rune Factory does have a strong emphasis on combat and dungeon crawling. Unfortunately, this title does not have meaningful content or story content past around 40 hours of play. You can take your time doing the main story, but at different parts some characters are unavailable or other features may not be accessible, so there is also a demand to get it done and over with. I thought that after maybe clearing the credits and being done with the main story that Id have more content to keep me busy, however I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This title has lots of different skills to raise, whether its combat in a lot of cool weapon types or the typical fishing, mining, and of course: farming. Theres not a lot of break in between the monotony though. I dont like how the days can be so long, so theres a lot of time where Im just running around aimlessly or I can get careless but not punished for that. A game with no real stakes or penalties is not very interesting to me. Theres lots of save points too, and that makes it so you can either re-load instead of paying the penalty to the infirmary if youre character dies. I think Stardew Valley and even the earlier Harvest Moon games set the bar so much higher. Rune Factory has great combat and pretty dungeons and puzzles, but it lacks any meaning to want to grind your skills past the credits. There is some post-credits content, like a maze dungeon, but I really have no desire to fish or cook meals for healing when I have no places to really go anymore that I need those items for. At that point, you are just leveling up skills to 100% a game that has no real rewards for doing such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The place where Rune Factory does excel is as a dating sim. If you like dating sim games and are willing to put in the time to get items/gifts for the character(s) you prefer to court, then that is some of the purpose of playing past the credits. I think that if I were to ever play Rune Factory 5, I would take my time in doing the main story content and focus on just farming and trying to give all the other skills a chance, but Id be really inclined to want to unlock more areas to use my items at. A farming game that emphasizes combat before farming isnt necessarily a bad thing, but when there is no more content or areas left to really use combat anymore, there is just a place where you can do farming for no real good reason. If the main story content required more actual farming or gathering of materials, it would give real meaning to all the different skills in the game including farming. Instead, farming, gathering skills, etc are used primarily to prepare and stock up for a dungeon run. When the dungeons are over, there is not a lot of reward or enjoyment left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rune Factory 5 is visually pretty and has an intriguing cast, but it is all style with no substance. I recommend to those that do wish to play this title, that they take their time, enjoy the game for what it is, and be very patient. Theres lots of hours you can pour into Rune Factory 5, and if you are looking for an endless endeavor: then look no further and check out this title. To me, this is like playing Stardew Valley on JRPG crack, and while I love Stardew and JRPGs... I cant say I find crack to be of worth.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/pokemonbdsp.html</id>
    <title>Pokemon Brilliant Diamond &amp; Shining Pearl [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/pokemonbdsp.html" />
    <published>2025-02-23T01:15:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-23T01:15:38-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/orange.png" alt="[!]"&gt; Double review: I played both Brilliant Diamond and Shining Pearl, and like most titles: pick which legendary on the box you like the most... (thats how you pick your poison)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/red.png" alt="[X]"&gt; These are the worst remakes in the Pokemon franchise. Outsourced development, glitches upon release, and most of all there is nothing truly remade or integrated into the Gen VIII architecture.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt="[*]"&gt; As these games are faithful remakes, it may be worth the playthrough for those that have not played the original Diamond and Pearl. However, I recommend Platinum version for the best Gen IV experience.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt="[*]"&gt; This game features some QoL, such as HMs are integrated to the Poketch.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sinnoh region was always barren until you beat the Elite 4 and Cynthia, and get that post-game magic. I was excited to go back to the modern Sinnoh again, with some new features and QoL. However, these titles did not deliver. Nintendo/Game Freak outsourced the development of these titles to ILCA, and while they did a great job at polishing up a 2.5D DS title into a 3D graphics version for Switch, there was not much additions or creative innovation in these remakes. I cant exactly attack ILCA for this, as they were tasked with a job to make faithful remakes. These titles arent exactly like the original Diamond/Pearl, as they include QoL, such as HMs integrated into the Poketch, and the underground is revamped (in actuality, it is just prettier).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I travel through Sinnoh, through the endless bidoofs, I remember that Diamond/Pearl era wasnt exactly the best for those actual titles. Platinum version and HeartGold/SoulSilver were the titles in Gen IV that made it the best. What made HeartGold/SoulSilver amazing, along with any other Pokemon remake of an older generation, is that these titles have new features that reflect the newer Gen as well as interact with the games of that Gen. Brilliant Diamond and Shining Pearl are not brilliant or shining enough to interact with Sword or Shield (being that these titles are made in Gen VIII). It would be cool if they added Dynamax to Diamond and Pearl. It wouldve been awesome to have Gen VIII Pokemon in Sinnoh underground, or at least make them tradeable. Without any extra features, I am just reminded of how truly empty the Sinnoh region is until the credits roll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The greatest disrespect of the newer Pokemon titles is that they are unashamed to release a title with glitches. These two titles are mostly patched and mostly clean now, but how does the biggest franchise in the world do that to their fans? Pokemon was always an experience, where the games had some sort of consistency where we would be thrilled with new features but also enjoy the integral parts that make it a mainline Pokemon title. Now, Game Freak plays it safe and wants to release titles that are easy to make and coast off the name of Pokemon, and now in order to mass-market more effectively: outsource development. I know that the team was probably focused on developing Arceus, and that these titles were kind of a way to give a teaser to that, however I find it hard to believe that there couldnt be a better budget for these titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good news is, if you are new to Pokemon, you could potentially enjoy these titles. Perhaps, a better route than playing these titles though is just playing Platinum version. If you really have to play a new 3D title and cant enjoy the DS graphics of Platinum, then I guess play these and youll probably enjoy them. I just think that the new trend in Pokemon is that the fans deserve a lot better than what they are being given...&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/tokyomiragesessions.html</id>
    <title>Tokyo Mirage Sessions #FE Encore [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/tokyomiragesessions.html" />
    <published>2025-02-22T23:52:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-22T23:52:16-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/green.png" alt=""&gt; the worlds of Shin Megami Tensei and Fire Emblem cross-over to make this amazing JRPG, which is an amazing gift for fans of both these series as well as for #jp, /jp/, JRPG fans and Japanese entertainment fans.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; The gameplay and combat of this title mostly reflects SMT, utilizing mechanics and systems from both SMT and Fire Emblem. This is a turn-based game with emphasis on combos. This is not a tactical grid RPG. That being said, this game has a perfect balance of SMT and FE.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I actually dive into this review, Id like to clarify my background with both these series. I dont think it is important you play any of these games before this title, as it does stand on its own, however as a fan of both Shin Megami Tensei and Fire Emblem for well over 20 years, I couldnt help but be excited to finally play this title. For fans and non-fans, there is some cosmetics from SMT/Persona, but the real star characters from this cross-over are the Demon/Persona (called Mirages in this title) versions of Fire Emblem 1 and Fire Emblem Awakening characters. If you are a fan of Archanea/Ylisse Fire Emblem, then youll be really happy to enjoy these characters in their SMT-esque forms. Other than that, expect more SMT-style battle mechanics as well as dungeon-crawling. The skills and magic are a fusion of SMT and FE, and I especially like the rock-paper-scissors (sword-lance-axe) of FE being inherited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from the SMT and FE cross-over aspects of this title, this title is centered around the Japanese pop/entertainment industry, and anyone that is #jp, /jp/ OG status will definitely like the references and energy of this title. While you do get to explore a good amount in Tokyo, this is not as extensive as I would have liked it to be. Fans of Persona 5 or any other game with Tokyo exploration will be underwhelmed with this title in that aspect. The real enthusiasm and life is from the J-pop tracks and music videos throughout the game. There are side-stories and side-quests that I recommend you dive into before you clear the game. There are two ending to this game, and the true ending isnt much different but you can accomplish this easily by just making sure to do all the side-stories. In that sense, I dont really like that lack of mystery and it is less demanding of a replay. I really enjoyed the characters a lot, and wish there was support links like in Persona or even marriage at the end of the title or something to keep the ending interesting and unique for each playthrough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the shortcomings of this title, which are small and few, I will say that I look forward to playing again in Lunatic mode and that will make for a fun New Game+ play of a title that I really enjoyed. (as well as enjoyed listening to repetitively to the tracks on the events theater) My only true complaint is that I wish there was more in this title. The Tokyo Mirage concept has potential and draws from iconic series and themes, and it is a shame to see that this title will most likely be buried underneath all the titles that come after it. Most cross-overs are just a cash grab, but this game stands on its own feet, gives anyone playing a good time and gives the fans what they deserve. I hope that Atlus and/or Intelligent Systems get together again to collaborate and give both these series another chance to cross-over.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/pokemonletsgoeevee.html</id>
    <title>Pokemon Lets Go Eevee [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/pokemonletsgoeevee.html" />
    <published>2025-02-15T22:44:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-15T22:44:01-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" title="[*]"&gt; This is a great place to start if you are new to Pokemon (or play Lets Go Pikachu if you prefer Pikachu more).&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" title="[*]"&gt; This is basically like playing Yellow version except with Eevee, and new graphics and conveniences.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/orange.png" title="[!]"&gt; Im not sure if Id recommend the purchase of this title unless you really like Eevee or really just want to collect any Pokemon title that exists. Dont fall for the nostalgia buy. The best Gen I nostalgia is the real thing, or play Gen II or Gen I remakes.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/orange.png" title="[!]"&gt; I dont recommend this game if you are looking for a more serious title or RPG. Even for a Pokemon game, there is even more emphasis on the cuteness and excessive collection of cute mons, so this is not a title for serious RPG lovers.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/red.png" title="[x]"&gt; All wild encounters in this game use a similar mechanic to Pokemon GO the mobile game, and that is a huge deal breaker for some people.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels good to be back in the Kanto region, but with a new twist, I get to have Eevee as my starter, and we both get to have all sorts of cute outfits as well as Eevee getting some custom moves that are exclusive only to this game. Eevee is a very powerful mon in this game as you can use items to increase his stats and they can learn lots of cool moves corresponding to all the different Eeveelutions. (sorry, but you cant evolve the Eevee starter in this game, and why would you? For once, you get to let your Eevee be an Eevee and actually stand a chance in battle!!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game incorporates mega-evolutions and Alola region versions of older mons, which is consistent with most remakes that they would include the new with the old. However, Gen I remakes Fire Red/Leaf Green included breeding and other features that were not included in the Lets Go titles. There is also a limited number of mons in this game, which is now the new trend in Pokemon games, which is rather annoying if you got mons youd love to bring over and use. This title is just Yellow version with a lot of polish (without substance) and the simple annoyances/limitations of a mobile game. If you dont like Pokemon GO, then definitely dont play this game because wild encounters are similar to the mechanics of that game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ill be honest with you...&lt;/i&gt; I do like this game and did have some fun. I like the playful nature of it, and if you want more out of the game you can get a lot of play out of this game if you are into the shiny grind or whatever. &lt;i&gt;That being said...&lt;/i&gt; there just are a lot better titles for Pokemon that deserve more attention than this, even some of the newer ones. I am happy that Eevee has a title now that it deserves, but I only bought this title because I wanted to get every Pokemon title I could get at the time. Playing it with friends and enjoying seeing Pokemon in the over-world was really cool, nicknaming Pokemon funny names, etc (the closest we get to a Lets Play or steaming live in prison). I can appreciate that Game Freak gave us the opportunity to go back to Kanto again, but for my next time in Kanto Id rather play Gen I, Gen II, or the Gen I remakes.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/prison_cell020625.html</id>
    <title>prison cell drawing 1</title>
    <link href="/posts/prison_cell020625.html" />
    <published>2025-02-06T21:38:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-06T21:38:47-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://booru.gikopoi.com/_images/5b064b28056eb89c95093e353827db44/228%20-%20akai%20blueprint%20cad%20cell%20prison%20prison_cell.png" width="300" height="500" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- &lt;u&gt;Moving clockwise from top left&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toilet/sink&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bunk beds w/ ladder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cabinets/shelves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table/desks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- &lt;u&gt;My thoughts on next blueprint&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I forgot the cell door too.... so, I'm missing some things, and am going to refine this overtime with more detail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hopefully the prison cell CAD drawing commences, along with other fun blueprint/floorplan ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic 2d CAD is fun, but I'm also reminded I've gotten rusty and need to do floorplanning more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- &lt;u&gt;Benefits of making blueprints&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is good practice of design principles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good for brain health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almost like another form of meditation for me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Useful to have blueprints to demonstrate when I'm telling (prison) stories&lt;/li&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/megadimensionneptuniavii.html</id>
    <title>Megadimension Neptunia VII [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/megadimensionneptuniavii.html" />
    <published>2025-02-06T21:29:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-06T21:29:40-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/green.png"&gt; This game emits strong JRPG qualities, ecchi vibes, and takes meta to a whole other level. The Neptunia franchise is in good hands, and doesnt stop modernizing yet maintains its integrity as a JRPG.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png"&gt; [VII stands for Victory II] You do not need to play any of the previous Neptunia titles to enjoy this game, not even its direct predecessor Hyperdimension Neptunia Victory.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png"&gt; Please keep in mind: the Neptunia titles do have a story, however there is an emphasis on parody/references as this is a meta title. (give yourself a break and have fun when playing, remember that there is lots of plot!)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/orange.png"&gt; If you are not in anyway interested in waifu/ecchi/fanservice/CG hunting, these games can be a bit much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hyperdimension Neptunia franchise has been doing its thing since its original title came out on PS3, and that is being meta as meta can get. These girls will definitely catch you slipping, and if you are in the business of getting the next waifu or love to collect that ecchi and CG, then this title is definitely for you. I spent probably around 220 hours on the title, and now that is mostly grinding for materials to craft weapons, items, etc. Idea Factory does a good job of making games that utilize the drops from monsters to make equips, and that is where Neptunia truly shines as not just a JRPG, but as an RPG itself. Even though I could say that this title gets underwhelming when I have my characters over-leveled, I still really enjoyed making sure to 100% because there are technically 3 endings to this title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For newcomers to Hyperdimension Neptunia, just imagine a world where every major console is basically an ecchi anime girl and rules their own respective nations. The original concept was the console war (in reference to the seventh console war between Xbox 360, PS3, and Wii), and they definitely expanded upon that with the newer titles, making room for references to other consoles/systems as well as other references to games, anime/manga, etc. So if you like Japanese video games or anime, definitely give the Neptunia series a try. If you want to have fun while you JRPG, Neptunia is definitely the way to go. There are some mechanical flaws with this title though, especially in dungeons when you use a strike to initiate preemptive attacks. Im not sure if the developers purposefully left things to be a bit off for this title, but I wouldnt be surprised as Idea Factory likes to have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely for a prisoner, this title is worth it, as you are thirsty for that CG and have a lot of time to commit to the CG hunting grind that this game presents. This title was worth every minute for me, but it is truly understandable that someone would not 100% it as that takes a lot of time and dedication. While this title does do a great job of using modern turn-based mechanics and is a great JRPG, I do think that there are other titles worth pouring in 100s of hours into. I do have more Neptunia titles to catch up on, and would love to play the remakes (including this title's remake), but life is a bit too hectic and it can be very difficult to fit in a demanding series such as Neptunia into the mix. I know this though, that Neptunias world is waiting for me anytime I need it, and it wont disappoint in scale thats for sure.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/eastward.html</id>
    <title>Eastward [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/eastward.html" />
    <published>2025-01-24T21:44:10-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-24T21:44:10-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/gold.png"&gt; Certified Indie Gold, and even with its limitations, Eastward evokes retro vibes and gives a thought-provoking story and escape to another world.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/orange.png"&gt; This game is a short-play (~20-30 hours) so for those of you that want a long story driven game with lots of content, this is not for you.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png"&gt; I think that I really enjoyed the mini-game Earth Born in this title just as much as Eastward, so in a way Im reviewing two games here. (I really want Earth Born on my phone or something for when Im waiting someplace!!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eastward was an indie title promoted by Nintendo, and a lot of us playing the Switch in prison were really intrigued by the indie scene we never really got to see flourish out there. Of course, Eastward was a title floating around the prison, and I am so happy I got to play it. A lot of guys that dont generally go for story-driven titles were really impressed by Eastwards retro vibes and creative life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the platformer/Zelda-esque puzzles as well as the clean combat that makes you work for it, but yet there is a fun and intuitive side to things. Switching between the two protagonists at times also reminds me of other titles as well. The awesome thing about Eastward is that before the game really truly starts, you get access to Earth Born, a mini-game accessible in each town through a game console outside a store (usually) that houses a gachapon for collectables/items that can be used in the mini-game. This game is a classic JRPG with some roguelite qualities to it (mainly in the deathloop aspect rather than procedural-generation/random-generation). This game was super fun, and I think I poured in over 20 hours on it so that my Eastward playthrough is a lot longer (45 hours to be exact) than the average player. Earth Born ties into a lot of the story as well, but it really is just begging for you to go back and play it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now on to Eastward: it is basically an escape/adventure game, but there is a lot of different paces throughout. This title is not cinematic-led, but rather like classic games it is led by event-editor scenes. Even so, it is really easy to be drawn in and with new technology, there is a recreating 16-bit new-school retro titles really gives it an edge. I would say the only real gripe I have about this title is that I wish there was more, or at least some new modes to unlock at the end. I think Eastward is a great title for anyone to play, and in a world where games are over 100 hours of play, this humble game lets you just chill and feel like you are a world where gaming can be gaming and not just a vicious, endless escapism.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/pokemonlegendsarceus.html</id>
    <title>Pokemon Legends: Arceus [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/pokemonlegendsarceus.html" />
    <published>2025-01-18T13:00:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-18T13:00:03-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/green.png" title=""&gt; This is a step in the right direction for the Pokemon franchise. This game includes just enough Action and RPG to bring fans what theyve been searching for in a true, contemporary Pokemon RPG.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" title="*"&gt; I was impressed and enjoyed this title, however I did feel like the only issue was that I wish there was more. DLCs would have actually been a great addition to this game, as it has great end-game content and grind to it, but there was just so much more they could have done with this title.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/orange.png" title="!"&gt; While you dont need to play any prior Pokemon titles to enjoy this game, I think that having an understanding of Gen IV/Sinnoh can amplify the value of the story in this title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pokemon was not my first RPG by far, but it was the game that solidified my love for RPGs. All other RPGs that follow it in my favorites are ones that allow customization of your party and building new strategies for new situations. Pokemon never was the most complicated of RPGs, and as the mainline series progresses, we see a lack of challenge as Game Freak strives to play it safe and not take lots of risks in their design and development of the games. This has made it so that long-time fans of the franchise, and for me being a fan since its inception, really have veered away from the franchise due to heavy disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will say with enthusiasm that this was not the case for Pokemon Legends: Arceus. While it was not as extensive in move-sets, without abilities, lacking in weather/terrain mechanics, and other things that simplified the Turn-Based battle system, it was a game that had RPG elements that give what the fans were looking for. It was not open-world, but the open-zone nature of it was just fine. The ability to use different mounts to re-explore areas or reach new parts of the map was a new, contemporary-style development of the earliest travel mechanics Gen Is HM techniques such as Surf or Fly that gave you the ability to traverse efficiently and adventure places you could not before. Being able to move faster, swim, climb, fly/glide, dig for treasure etc. on each mount gave the game life that made it feel like I was apart of something bigger. (it reminded me of Monster Hunter or the fun of WoW mounts, and that was just something I never thought a Pokemon game would ever implement)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The action mechanics of Arceus included the ability of wild Pokemon to attack your trainer, sneaking around and building different approaches to catch Pokemon without having to battle them, and also boss battles that incorporated action mechanics alongside turn-based battles that are traditional among Pokemon. This game was a step in the right direction, and it was always fun to use different items to incapacitate monsters while you sneak around and then catching them. Gathering items and then crafting your own steampunk-esque Pokeballs and other items made the game/grind very entertaining and worth something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among all others, this approach to the Sinnoh region (in this title, as the feudal era and called the Hisui region) gave a lot of life to a previously barren region in its mainline titles. Arceus was given the credit that he deserves as a Mythical Pokemon that created the world of Pokemon. The endgame/post-credits grind to actually get Arceus was also amazing, and it really evoked the old style of Pokemon where the endgame is the real game. Pokemon Legends: Arceus is definitely a title that was amazing and stands strong alone, but makes you wish there was more at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/coldsteeliv.html</id>
    <title>The Legend of Heroes: Trails of Cold Steel IV [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/coldsteeliv.html" />
    <published>2025-01-15T23:06:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-15T23:06:48-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/green.png"&gt; A great conclusion to the Cold Steel games and the major story arc of the franchise. Recommended for any JRPG fans. 100+ hour adventure.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/orange.png"&gt; I recommend playing Cold Steel III (if you arent trying to start all the way from the first title) before playing, as it is highly necessary to understand the story in this title.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/orange.png"&gt; This title has some bloat to it when it comes to the RPG/design sensibilities.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png"&gt; The Legend of Heroes titles (also referred as Trails or Kiseki) are all about world-building, so you can play the Cold Steel titles before the other major titles if you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has been following &lt;i&gt;Kiseki&lt;/i&gt; for awhile that has not played this title needs to get up to speed and do so. This is everything that fans have been waiting for. This title brings all 3 of the major story arc games (Trails in the Sky trilogy, the two Crossbell [from Zero/to Azure] games, and the tetralogy Cold Steel) together and the story converges as one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I do think fans will be very interested in this title, it is definitely not the entry title for Kiseki or even the Cold Steel games. Fans will appreciate old, familiar faces appearing and being playable, yet the newcomer will be lost. Even for a JRPG fan like myself, I was not as immersed as I was in Cold Steel III. The problem with these titles is that there are a lot of skills/crafts/etc that are very redundant. I found that with the correct orbment (sort of like materia in FFVII) set-up that I can be even more destructive to enemies than with the ultimate or best stuff. It really makes the grind for those items really useless in a way. This title is filled with lots of useless skills, if you know what you are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The minigames in this game are expanded. There is the return of Vantage Masters, and this time around the computer player is a lot more sophisticated. There are more cards available, so there is even more reason to change-up your deck. I had a lot of fun with building decks and tweaking my strategy depending on my opponent. There is the addition of other minigames, such as Pom Pom Party. It is sort of like Doctor Mario. The ability to take a break from talking, running around, hitting up missions, and just the grind in general is really nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This title really was enjoyable, and it has more character development and story than the other title. (especially in terms of optional content, bonding scenes, etc) That is great for myself as a fan, but I found that even with all the variety of characters to have in my party that I was not really interested in customization as much as I thought I would. The game does make starting over fun, but early on in there is not much optional content available, making it fairly linear. Once the optional content and world expansion occurs, theres really at that point not a lot making me want to dive deeper. I felt more obligated than excited to do side content in this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cold Steel IV is a great title nonetheless, but it suffers a bit from the bloated nature that most games are taking up. Content for the sake of content and without any real coherence. There is, however, a part of me that would love to replay this title along with all the other Cold Steel games because the story does have a special place in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/holiday2024.html</id>
    <title>Gikopoi Holiday 2024</title>
    <link href="/posts/holiday2024.html" />
    <published>2025-01-08T22:11:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-08T22:11:16-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is now 2025, but we got to end 2024 on a good note at Gikopoi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just a recap of my fun on Gikopoi for Holidays 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been pretty active streaming, especially when #AFK. I usually stream a lot of Nightcore playlists, but I change it up too sometimes with a variety of content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had the first annual Gikopoi Christmas Nights of Nightcore event as well. We enjoyed 2 days straight of Nightcore DJing from yours truly. It is such a blessing to be in the modern world and be able to DJ without actually being present. Thank you Gikopoi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://booru.gikopoi.com/_images/2557e88b9f5caf95cdb3c4cf99e9e4df/188%20-%20akai%20christmas%20event%20gikoxmas%20holiday%20keyvisual%20love%20luv%20nightcore%20xmas.jpg" width="300" height="500" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Key Visual - Christmas Nights of Nightcore 2024&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Key Visual stamp of approval from Archduke, except oppai too much I guess. Noted, will work on that..)
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://play.gikopoi.com/characters/akai/front-standing.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is maybe unrelated to Holiday celebrations, but there is now an Akai/wizard hat Giko available for &lt;a href="https://play.gikopoi.com"&gt;play on Gikopoi&lt;/a&gt; now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what are you waiting for? Let's &lt;a href="https://play.gikopoi.com"&gt;play Gikopoi&lt;/a&gt; today!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This blog post provided as my dues for using server space for my ramblings, and due to a binding contract of Love and Friendship to Archduke)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/coldsteeliii.html</id>
    <title>The Legend of Heroes: Trails of Cold Steel III [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/coldsteeliii.html" />
    <published>2025-01-08T22:03:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-08T22:03:09-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/green.png" alt=""&gt; This title is definitely a cinematic/story JRPG that stands on its own feet. If you are looking for a 100+ hour exciting, yet somewhat grindy, adventure (with replay value), then look no further and try this title out.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; Game played in Nightmare difficulty setting with only one playthrough.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; This title is 3 of 4 titles in the Cold Steel titles, and it is the first chapter of the second phase of the Cold Steel story. There is a movie/summary section in the game that can get you up to speed, if you prefer to skip the first two titles. (although I recommend playing the whole tetralogy)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; The Legend of Heroes titles (also referred as &lt;i&gt;Trails&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;Kiseki&lt;/i&gt;) are all about world-building, so you can play the Cold Steel titles before the other major titles if you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having played other Kiseki titles, it was absolutely paramount that I continue Rean Schwarzers adventures in the Cold Steel titles, and also be able to see the culmination of other regions stories come together as one. This title does not necessarily conclude anything or bring it all together, but it does set it up so that the next game (Cold Steel IV) can fulfill that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting aside the massive world-building that Kiseki does, this title is an amazing JRPG experience that has lots of optional content that you want to do before the deadlines are over. There is a bit of life simulation tasks in this title, but they bring you into combat or into situations that are exciting. So while there is Persona-vibes with a calendar, there is no divide really between simulation and dungeon crawling. You will have a lot of cut-scenes, reading and talking to do in this title, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game does have great turn-based battles and tactics. The systems are a bit reminiscent of materia from Final Fantasy VII, but it does add some new things to the conversation. Setting up your team to lack delay and be set up next in line for fighting is a very big part of building strategy in these games. (especially in the more difficult settings) There are a few ways to break the system in this game, which is a bit disappointing for someone who enjoys systems that require deep strategies and also changing it up. I cant help but break the game if I know how to. Especially since it isnt cheating, it is just utilizing the best strategy available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love that this title has optional boss fights that are super invigorating and exciting. Games that have exciting side content that isnt overly demanding or boring make a really big impact. This is not an open-world game, but it really does allow you to feel free to explore. There is a lot of purpose in the narratives and story-telling, and you really feel like you are immersed in the world. There is obviously a grindy trend to this game, as it is a JRPG. It just comes with the territory. I cant help but be inspired to keep the grind going with all my cute, cool and sexy costumes for the characters though. Beside if you get bored of the grind, you can also play a mini-game/card game Vantage Masters with friends/NPCs. Im definitely an avid player of JRPGs, but the Kiseki games really suck you in and the story telling is very engrossing. If you enjoy this story, you will want to definitely play the other titles to figure out the other pieces of the puzzle in this story. The game comes equip with a whole section of movies that can get you up to speed with the Cold Steel story-line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for the most tactically-demanding title or anything super different in a JRPG, you wont find that here. You will, however, find a great story and a world full of mystery that begs you to unravel it. As long as you find value in that, you will really be hooked on Kiseki for sure.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/metroiddread.html</id>
    <title>Metroid Dread [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/metroiddread.html" />
    <published>2025-01-08T22:02:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-08T22:02:43-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/red.png" alt=""&gt; This game is not a long play. Most players it took around 15-25 hours to complete this title.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/orange.png" alt=""&gt; If you are looking for a true homage to Metroidvania and going on an adventure, read my &lt;a href="/posts/hollowknight.html"&gt;article on Hollow Knight&lt;/a&gt; and maybe that will be convincing enough to embark on your next Metroidvania game.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; Seasoned or non-seasoned Metroidvania players will have minimal to no trouble clearing this game.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; If you dont like games that are more graphics than they are anything else, definitely skip this title for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last review, I commented briefly about Metroid Dread. I likened this title to eating a fun-sized candy. That is not to diminish the amount of excitement I did have in this title, but to merely state that this game was fun treat yet it makes you really wish you had something larger in scale of the same variety. Essentially, Metroid Dread is all the polish that a contemporary title needs, yet lacks the substance that gives us something new to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This title is essentially classic Metroidvania, and you can expect to get lots of new upgrades to your suit and have to navigate around new biomes and terrains, and of course the backtracking and working around typical platformer obstacles. The main issue with this title is that there is a lack of variety of exploration, and the game plays super linear for a newer title. You do not go on your own adventure in this one, and there is no optional/bonus content to enjoy. Having some challenging bosses to the side or some fun objectives to do are a nice mold breaker when you are bored with the main story content of a game. (If you are looking for a Metroidvania title that gives you this joy and adds a lot of original content value, then I recommend reading my &lt;a href="/posts/hollowknight.html"&gt;article on Hollow Knight&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did enjoy the overall graphics and cinematic play of this game, and the cinematic-led battle mechanics were a nice touch. I cant help but say that this was the distraction that was delivered to make your forget that you are only playing a 15-25 hour game. (depending on your skill level with platformers and/or Metroidvania) The final boss is enjoyable enough though, and it would be nice to continue the narrative that Dread carries on in the story. However, if I wanted to enjoy a good story only I would be looking for a light novel series or manga. In the world of games, we want an interactive experience (which includes a good story and world) and Dread did not deliver the interactivity that I wouldve loved to have with in such a fantastic world that Metroid really lays out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully one day we will possibly see a good Metroid title that stays true to the Metroidvania platformer style. It seems like Nintendo is more interested in remastering and exploring the Prime titles, which are very good, but this deprives those of us that want a 2d platforming experience with the Metroid games. Unfortunately, the direction that most Nintendo games suffer from is that they are moving away from what makes them a fantastic, integral experience in favor of massively, successively producing titles and giving the masses a title that they can easily beat, or perhaps can sit on their backlog for the ends of time.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/hollowknight.html</id>
    <title>Hollow Knight [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/hollowknight.html" />
    <published>2024-12-25T18:35:51-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-25T18:35:51-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/gold.png" alt="certified indie gold" title="certified indie gold"&gt; Certified that this is game is pure indie gold, and this game is a must play.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/green.png" alt=""&gt; Metroidvania fans, noobs, and haters should all try this game, it is worth the work and the play.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; There is still a lot I'd love to (re-)explore in this game, and perhaps will do a post where I revisit this title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metroidvania titles are dime a dozen these days. With the lack of new Castlevania titles being released and the newest Metroid title (Metroid Dread, not counting the Metroid Prime remaster as a new title) being a small-scale game that is reminiscent of eating fun-size candy (or some other quick treat), it really makes a fan like me of metroidvania crave something new and exciting. Hollow Knight was exactly what I was looking for, but more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hollow Knight has a really unique weapon and equip system, that makes for lots of different approaches to Bossing in a metroidvania title. This game is full of exciting biomes and scenery, as well as a riveting piano soundtrack that literally made me just sit there and close my eyes and just listen to the ambience for awhile. I really enjoyed the playful yet serious nature of Hollownest. The voice acting is spot-on and just makes me feel comfortable in this dark, confusing world I had to piece together. I never had Boss fights make me bust into laughter yet have to get real serious in a quick second as to not would be the cause of imminent death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For metroidvania, this title can be forgiving, but doesn't remove the challenges that you'd expect in a platformer of a high caliber. I enjoyed the fact that this game for the most part lets you go on your own adventure, and does not hold your hand at all. The maps are nice, easy to read, helpful, and worth the purchase when you get to a new biome. The game embodies all the great things of both Metroid and Castlevania.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gameplay is very smooth for this title, and it is a very clean game. I never felt like there was any real bugs or glitches, or encountered anything that felt like it just didn't belong. I never felt like any boss had any cheap advantages or that I could only beat something with one approach. Hollow Knight is not limiting, and it is also not going to cheat you out of a win against a Boss. There is no gimmicks or games, yet it is a game and it makes you want more. Team Cherry was very careful in releasing this title, and they had good design planning and sensibilities when it came to making a complete game. There is a lot of optional content just waiting for you to explore. The story is definitely not exactly approachable, but you can piece it together and find your own meanings to different things. You do definitely feel immersed in that world once you got the audio on. It is just so hard to put down at times. There is a good amount of puzzles and figuring things out, and that makes the game exciting for someone like me. This game is everything I wanted out of a metroidvania title, and is just perfect for me. I enjoy the characters, the story, and the world of Hollownest. We are still waiting on a sequel to this title, and it is definitely exciting to see that there is more left to such an awesome concept and world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone that is new to metroidvania should definitely give this a try. If you don't like metroidvania, still give it a try. And if you LOVE metroidvania, but have not played Hollow Knight, you need to play this game.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/stardew1.5.4.html</id>
    <title>Stardew Valley 1.5.4 [Game Review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/stardew1.5.4.html" />
    <published>2024-12-23T10:45:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-23T10:45:33-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/gold.png" alt="certified indie gold" title="certified indie gold"&gt; Certified that this is game is pure indie gold, and this game is a must play.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; This version is the author's first play of stardew valley, so there will be no comparisons of 1.5 and the initial build and/or older versions.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; Please be aware Stardew Valley 1.6 is out, and there is a possibility I may revisit and review this game's updated versions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, I would read in magazines about Stardew Valley. Solo developer &lt;a href="https://www.stardewvalley.net/author/concernedape/"&gt;ConcernedApe&lt;/a&gt; is truly an inspiration to any game developer or anyone that is set out to make something, go through with it, and actually finish it. There is a lot love put into this title.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;I have experience with the &lt;i&gt;former&lt;/i&gt; Harvest Moon (now Story of Seasons) titles (such as the N64 title, Friends of Mineral Town and A Wonderful Life), played Rune Factory 4 (complete) &amp; 5, and other farming sim games. This game not only is inspired and takes from these games, but it amplifies the formula to new levels. I like how the day clock is a lot faster than other farming games, challenging me to really coordinate what I need to do for the day. I really enjoy the new school retro 16-bit that this title evokes. When I first started playing, I was more interested in the characters and town life, and got into fishing and mining more so than farming. I took my time with everything, and tried just about everything. As I was incarcerated while playing this game, I did not have wiki access, so I had to figure out a lot of the game myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the use of the hotbar for equips/items usage, the creative and challenging fishing game to catch fish, the minigames at the Stardrop Saloon, and just the overall culture of Pelican Town and Stardew Valley. This game is a farming sim at its core, so if you are not interested in that style of game or you've tried Harvest Moon and do not like it, then perhaps it might not be for you. However, as said above this game sets the bar pretty high for those titles, so maybe it would be worth giving a shot even if you don't like the farming sim genre. There is a lot of mysterious imbued in the story still, and the world that the Valley is in is definitely one that I am interested in exploring. ConcernedApe has more games left in him, and I personally think that these games will expand on this world that he desires to create. (See &lt;a href="https://www.hauntedchocolatier.net/"&gt;Haunted Chocolatier&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having put well over 250 hours into this title, I got a lot out of this game. There is definitely still more I could do to have fun customizing my farm and my island house. I spent a lot of time making Starfruit wine and utilizing the whole cellar floor to age what I can and then just sell the rest. It was fun to try new things in this game, mess around with crafting, see what comes out a preserve jar, and just the overall experience of trying to 100% this game was fun and it really makes you want it. This title is easily driving and will definitely pull you in if you give it a chance. There is going to be more playthroughs of Stardew for me, as it is updated overtime as well as a very vibrant and active modding community. And yet it seems that even though there are a lot of great mods, this game is just perfect even without them, however anything to change it up is appreciated so that's where mods do come in. My love for it will probably drive me into the modding direction for some time before I decide to do another vanilla playthrough again. Although from the looks of it, the new additions to Stardew could keep me busy for another 250+ hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stardew Valley is not a game full of redundancies in its design. It has a lot of different approaches for success, yet has no disappointments when it comes to the challenge that games need to present. Everything goes together and is intricately connected. This is how games are meant to be. In an era where games are not trying to be games, this one stands on its feet and decides it wants to be a game. That is the real beauty of The Valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Journey in The Valley is long from over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support &lt;a href="https://www.stardewvalley.net/author/concernedape/"&gt;ConcernedApe&lt;/a&gt; and buy this game.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/2.html</id>
    <title>2</title>
    <link href="/posts/2.html" />
    <published>2024-12-22T22:08:10-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-22T22:08:10-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just a small update. This site is no longer generated using the &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/"&gt;Hugo software&lt;/a&gt;. This site, however, is now generated by its own software &lt;a href="https://github.com/archmageakai/gikoru"&gt;Gikoru&lt;/a&gt;. You can feel free to use it, change code, make it your own. It is just another project that was able to keep me stimulated and to knock the rust off for my python. The code is a bit messy anyway, or at least could use condensing. So, feel free to critique and clean as you see fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've got some other projects in the works anyways. &lt;a href="/sections/prison_game_reviews/"&gt;Prison Game Reviews&lt;/a&gt; are being written out of my notebook, where they were originally wrote. I do revise them or correct spelling/grammar when necessary. Of course, adding icons and images to the review are also &lt;i&gt;usually&lt;/i&gt; part of the process of transferring from physical to digital. I have a lot of chronicled works and notes that I have to transfer besides the Prison Game Reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, you can follow this site on a feed reader of your choice as it is &lt;a href="/index.atom"&gt;atom-ized&lt;/a&gt; now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later.&lt;/a&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/pokemonshield.html</id>
    <title>Pokemon Shield + Pokemon Shield Expansion Pass [Game review]</title>
    <link href="/posts/pokemonshield.html" />
    <published>2024-12-08T21:33:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-08T21:33:19-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/green.png" alt=""&gt; I loved this game so much, that I have over 1500 hours played.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/orange.png" alt=""&gt; Note: it is my opinion that this game is best played with the Expansion pass, to get the full experience.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; This game was my first Switch game, played while I was incarcerated&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; This game was played from beginning with DLCs loaded&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been a Pokemon fan since its inception in North America. My first Pokemon video game was Pokemon Blue on GBC. It is fitting that my first game on the Nintendo Switch would be a Pokemon title. Ownership of a console/handheld was not something I had the privilege/right (this dichotomy would keep us busy for awhile) as someone incarcerated. I had access to a variety of cellmates Plug&amp;amp;Play versions of systems (Atari, Sega Genesis, others), XBOX 360 (limited hours), and PS4 (limited hours), but being able to play a current system in a prison was a very big deal for a lot of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I purchased the Pokemon Shield game cartridge with the Expansion Pass included. It was well-worth the 90 USD spent, as I spent over 1500 hours playing this game. Even with the new Gen 9 titles &lt;em&gt;Pokemon Scarlet and Violet&lt;/em&gt; (which will be reviewed soon), I still found myself going back to this game. Most of these hours spent were shiny hunting, but a lot of the time was also spent in the Battle Tower and making Pokemon teams specialized for competitive battling. There is a lot of content included in these games, if you get the Expansion Pass. Without the Expansion Pass, I find that the Gen 8 base-game is very lacking, especially in endgame content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gen 8s location is based on the United Kingdom, and I liked a lot of what they did to keep us entertained with a lot of the pop culture references. However, I did find that the story in Gen 8 is lacking in real stakes. Team Yell is a nice ode to the British Punk Rock scene, but there is an overall lack of drive in the story. The story mostly just emphasizes the Gym Challenge, which has always been a big part of the games in the mainline Pokemon games. However, without a clear villain or obstacle, this made the story very linear in nature. The end of the story is where a lot of the twists occur, and it is a nice way to incorporate the Box Legendaries for sure. This is where the DLC content comes in. It does add a nice break from the monotony in the Galar region. That being said, Galar is a very beautiful location and I did enjoy the variety of biomes and had a deep appreciation for the Wild Area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed the Galarian versions of Slowpoke, Slowbro, and Slowking, which you only have access to at the Isle of Armour location provided by the Expansion Pass. I also really liked the Max Raid dungeon battles in the Crown Tundra, where you can catch lots of old legendary Pokemon as well as other fan favorites along the way. Gen 8 did a good job with the characters (including rivals like Hop or Marnie), and I do like the playful nature of rivalry that is pushed now in the series. (and there is still a little taste of the bitter/elitist rival from the earlier titles) Morpeko was also a really good addition, as this Generations Pikachu-like, cute little hamster with two different forms (Peckish and Hangry) it rotates between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with all the gripes about Pokemons mainline series being a bit more streamlined and just plain easy to play through, I am always so interested and love to see the new Pocket Monsters. Theres always something to look forward with a new Gen of Pokemon, whether the games are a hit or not. The real stars of the show are the monsters and the trainers. Pokemon is always going to be about the player and their story, and my story in the Pokemon world isnt over yet.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/1.html</id>
    <title>1</title>
    <link href="/posts/1.html" />
    <published>2024-11-25T01:26:49-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-11-25T01:26:49-05:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, this is AKAINES blog for reflections/meditations, game development, AKAINES soundworks and music production, video game talks/reviews, Jailhouse cooking and recipes, and whatever else it needs to be. That is all for now.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
