<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>akai.gikopoi.com</title><subtitle>generated by gikoru (on github: archmageakai/gikoru.git)</subtitle><updated>2024-12-25T17:56:39Z</updated><id>https://akai.gikopoi.com</id><author><name>akai</name></author><entry><id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/stardew1.5.4.html</id><title>Stardew Valley 1.5.4 [Game Review]</title><link href="/posts/stardew1.5.4.html" /><published>2024-12-23T10:45:33-05:00</published><summary>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/gold.png" alt="certified indie gold" title="certified indie gold"&gt; Certified that this is game is pure indie gold, and this game is a must play.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; This version is the author's first play of stardew valley, so there will be no comparisons of 1.5 and the initial build and/or older versions.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; Please be aware Stardew Valley 1.6 is out, and there is a possibility I may revisit and review this game's updated versions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, I would read in magazines about Stardew Valley. Solo developer &lt;a href="https://www.stardewvalley.net/author/concernedape/"&gt;ConcernedApe&lt;/a&gt; is truly an inspiration to any game developer or anyone that is set out to make something, go through with it, and actually finish it. There is a lot love put into this title.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;I have experience with the &lt;i&gt;former&lt;/i&gt; Harvest Moon (now Story of Seasons) titles (such as the N64 title, Friends of Mineral Town and A Wonderful Life), played Rune Factory 4 (complete) &amp; 5, and other farming sim games. This game not only is inspired and takes from these games, but it amplifies the formula to new levels. I like how the day clock is a lot faster than other farming games, challenging me to really coordinate what I need to do for the day. I really enjoy the new school retro 16-bit that this title evokes. When I first started playing, I was more interested in the characters and town life, and got into fishing and mining more so than farming. I took my time with everything, and tried just about everything. As I was incarcerated while playing this game, I did not have wiki access, so I had to figure out a lot of the game myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the use of the hotbar for equips/items usage, the creative and challenging fishing game to catch fish, the minigames at the Stardrop Saloon, and just the overall culture of Pelican Town and Stardew Valley. This game is a farming sim at its core, so if you are not interested in that style of game or you've tried Harvest Moon and do not like it, then perhaps it might not be for you. However, as said above this game sets the bar pretty high for those titles, so maybe it would be worth giving a shot even if you don't like the farming sim genre. There is a lot of mysterious imbued in the story still, and the world that the Valley is in is definitely one that I am interested in exploring. ConcernedApe has more games left in him, and I personally think that these games will expand on this world that he desires to create. (See &lt;a href="https://www.hauntedchocolatier.net/"&gt;Haunted Chocolatier&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having put well over 250 hours into this title, I got a lot out of this game. There is definitely still more I could do to have fun customizing my farm and my island house. I spent a lot of time making Starfruit wine and utilizing the whole cellar floor to age what I can and then just sell the rest. It was fun to try new things in this game, mess around with crafting, see what comes out a preserve jar, and just the overall experience of trying to 100% this game was fun and it really makes you want it. This title is easily driving and will definitely pull you in if you give it a chance. There is going to be more playthroughs of Stardew for me, as it is updated overtime as well as a very vibrant and active modding community. And yet it seems that even though there are a lot of great mods, this game is just perfect even without them, however anything to change it up is appreciated so that's where mods do come in. My love for it will probably drive me into the modding direction for some time before I decide to do another vanilla playthrough again. Although from the looks of it, the new additions to Stardew could keep me busy for another 250+ hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stardew Valley is not a game full of redundancies in its design. It has a lot of different approaches for success, yet has no disappointments when it comes to the challenge that games need to present. Everything goes together and is intricately connected. This is how games are meant to be. In an era where games are not trying to be games, this one stands on its feet and decides it wants to be a game. That is the real beauty of The Valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Journey in The Valley is long from over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support &lt;a href="https://www.stardewvalley.net/author/concernedape/"&gt;ConcernedApe&lt;/a&gt; and buy this game.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/2.html</id><title>2</title><link href="/posts/2.html" /><published>2024-12-22T22:08:10-05:00</published><summary>&lt;p&gt;Just a small update. This site is no longer generated using the &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/"&gt;Hugo software&lt;/a&gt;. This site, however, is now generated by its own software &lt;a href="https://github.com/archmageakai/gikoru"&gt;Gikoru&lt;/a&gt;. You can feel free to use it, change code, make it your own. It is just another project that was able to keep me stimulated and to knock the rust off for my python. The code is a bit messy anyway, or at least could use condensing. So, feel free to critique and clean as you see fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've got some other projects in the works anyways. &lt;a href="/sections/prison_game_reviews/"&gt;Prison Game Reviews&lt;/a&gt; are being written out of my notebook, where they were originally wrote. I do revise them or correct spelling/grammar when necessary. Of course, adding icons and images to the review are also &lt;i&gt;usually&lt;/i&gt; part of the process of transferring from physical to digital. I have a lot of chronicled works and notes that I have to transfer besides the Prison Game Reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, you can follow this site on a feed reader of your choice as it is &lt;a href="/index.atom"&gt;atom-ized&lt;/a&gt; now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later.&lt;/a&gt;</summary></entry><entry><id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/pokemonshield.html</id><title>Pokemon Shield + Pokemon Shield Expansion Pass [Game review]</title><link href="/posts/pokemonshield.html" /><published>2024-12-08T21:33:19-05:00</published><summary>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/wiz.png" alt="wizhat" title="wizhat"&gt; &lt;em&gt;TL;DR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/image/green.png" alt=""&gt; I loved this game so much, that I have over 1500 hours played.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/orange.png" alt=""&gt; Note: it is my opinion that this game is best played with the Expansion pass, to get the full experience.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; This game was my first Switch game, played while I was incarcerated&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="/image/pink.png" alt=""&gt; This game was played from beginning with DLCs loaded&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Played on a Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been a Pokemon fan since its inception in North America. My first Pokemon video game was Pokemon Blue on GBC. It is fitting that my first game on the Nintendo Switch would be a Pokemon title. Ownership of a console/handheld was not something I had the privilege/right (this dichotomy would keep us busy for awhile) as someone incarcerated. I had access to a variety of cellmate’s Plug&amp;amp;Play versions of systems (Atari, Sega Genesis, others), XBOX 360 (limited hours), and PS4 (limited hours), but being able to play a current system in a prison was a very big deal for a lot of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I purchased the Pokemon Shield game cartridge with the Expansion Pass included. It was well-worth the 90 USD spent, as I spent over 1500 hours playing this game. Even with the new Gen 9 titles &lt;em&gt;Pokemon Scarlet and Violet&lt;/em&gt; (which will be reviewed soon), I still found myself going back to this game. Most of these hours spent were shiny hunting, but a lot of the time was also spent in the Battle Tower and making Pokemon teams specialized for competitive battling. There is a lot of content included in these games, if you get the Expansion Pass. Without the Expansion Pass, I find that the Gen 8 base-game is very lacking, especially in endgame content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gen 8’s location is based on the United Kingdom, and I liked a lot of what they did to keep us entertained with a lot of the pop culture references. However, I did find that the story in Gen 8 is lacking in real stakes. Team Yell is a nice ode to the British Punk Rock scene, but there is an overall lack of drive in the story. The story mostly just emphasizes the Gym Challenge, which has always been a big part of the games in the mainline Pokemon games. However, without a clear villain or obstacle, this made the story very linear in nature. The end of the story is where a lot of the twists occur, and it is a nice way to incorporate the Box Legendaries for sure. This is where the DLC content comes in. It does add a nice break from the monotony in the Galar region. That being said, Galar is a very beautiful location and I did enjoy the variety of biomes and had a deep appreciation for the Wild Area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed the Galarian versions of Slowpoke, Slowbro, and Slowking, which you only have access to at the Isle of Armour location provided by the Expansion Pass. I also really liked the Max Raid dungeon battles in the Crown Tundra, where you can catch lots of old legendary Pokemon as well as other fan favorites along the way. Gen 8 did a good job with the characters (including rivals like Hop or Marnie), and I do like the playful nature of rivalry that is pushed now in the series. (and there is still a little taste of the bitter/elitist rival from the earlier titles) Morpeko was also a really good addition, as this Generation’s Pikachu-like, cute little hamster with two different forms (Peckish and Hangry) it rotates between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with all the gripes about Pokemon’s mainline series being a bit more streamlined and just plain easy to play through, I am always so interested and love to see the new Pocket Monsters. There’s always something to look forward with a new Gen of Pokemon, whether the games are a hit or not. The real stars of the show are the monsters and the trainers. Pokemon is always going to be about the player and their story, and my story in the Pokemon world isn’t over yet.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><id>https://akai.gikopoi.com/posts/1.html</id><title>1</title><link href="/posts/1.html" /><published>2024-11-25T01:26:49-05:00</published><summary>&lt;p&gt;Hello, this is AKAINES blog for reflections/meditations, game development, AKAINES soundworks and music production, video game talks/reviews, Jailhouse cooking and recipes, and whatever else it needs to be. That is all for now.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>